[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P,
> >好吧,好吧,欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,
This is Developing iOS Application, Winter of 2017,
这是开发iOS应用程序,2017年冬天,
And the only topic for today is a big one, Core Data,
唯一的今天是一个大主题,核心数据,
which is an object oriented database,
这是一个面向对象的数据库,
But before I dive into this,
但在我深入之前,
I'm actually going to revisit that demo we did last time
我要重新审视我们上次演示
just briefly, because we ran out of time and so
只是短暂的,因为我们跑的时间
I wasn't able to show you the refresh control,
我无法给你刷新控制,
Now I posted the code for it, so
现在我发布的代码,所以
I'm not gonna type all the code in here,
我不会输入所有的代码在这里,
But I'm just gonna briefly show you
但是我要简要地告诉你
how that refresh control worked, okay?
刷新控制是怎样工作的,好吗?
Okay, so we missed that,
好的,我们错过了,
So here is the app we had from last time,
这是应用程序从上次我们有,
By the way, I have modified our app
顺便说一下,我修改了我们的应用程序
here to change our request a little bit,
这一点,改变我们的要求
If you remember this line of code from last time,
如果你还记得这行代码从最后一次,
it used to just have the query,
以前只有查询,
But I've changed it to also filter out retweets and
但是我已经改变了它也过滤掉转发
I've also put on the safe filter, which hopefully will
我也戴上安全过滤器,这有望
make it so that when I do these look ups,
让它这样,当我做这些,
these sort of up looks, we don't get stuff on the screen,
这些看起来,我们没有得到的东西在屏幕上,
you know this is a family show,
你知道这是一个家庭,
so we don't want to see some of that stuff,
所以我们不想看到一些东西,
Anyway, hopefully, that'll work,
无论如何,希望,可以工作,
So let's go back here and
那么让我们回到这里
take a look at what this looks like,
看看这是什么样子,
There's my simulator right here,
这里有我的模拟器,
So let's go ahead and search,
让我们继续搜索,
Let's try Trump again and cross our fingers, all right,
让我们再次尝试Trump和交叉手指,好吧,
So that's not, I don't see anything too terrible there,
所以这不是,我没有看到任何太可怕了,
Okay so what we added was this UI where we can pull down,
所以我们添加这个UI可以拉下来,
Okay and it adds more tweets,
好的,它增加了更多的推文谈及这次慈善拍卖,
you see how it added a tweet there?
你看看它添加了一个推特吗?
We have the second pull right there,
我们有第二个拉,
this was with the first pull,
这是第一次拉,
And we pull down again, no tweets this time, okay?
我们拉下来,不推这一次,好吗?
So each time we pull down it's doing another twitter
所以每次我们拆掉做另一个twitter
fetch, and
取回,
may get more tweets depending if people are tweeting or not,
可能获得更多的tweet是否人发微博,
So let's take a look at the code to do this, again,
让我们看一看代码要做到这一点,再一次,
I posted this code, but
我发布了这段代码,但
we'll just look at it, I'm not gonna type it all in,
我们将看看它,我不会在类型,
we're just gonna look at it real quick,
我们要看它很快,
First of all, let's talk about how do I get this UI where
首先,让我们谈谈我怎么得到这个UI
we pull down and it calls a method, or whatever?
我们拉下,它调用一个方法,或任何?
So let's go to look in our storyboard,
让我们去看看我们的故事板,
All right, so here's our storyboard, and
好吧,这是我们的故事板
what I did was I just selected my table view controller and
我所做的是我只是选择我的表视图控制器和
I went down here to this refreshing,
我去下面这个让人耳目一新,
You see that refreshing choice?
你会看到令人耳目一新的选择?
And I changed it from disabled to enabled, and when I set it
我改变它从禁用启用,当我把它
to enabled nothing changed here in the UI,
启用任何UI,这里发生了巨大的变化
You can't see any spinning thing, but
你不能看到任何旋转的事情,但是
over here in the document outline it created this
在创建这个文档大纲
refresh control right here,
刷新控制这里,
And so I can control drag from the document outline just as I
所以我可以控制文档大纲正如我的阻力
can through here,
可以在这里通过,
So all I did to make this work is I just brought up
所以我所做的这个工作是我长大的
my controller right here,
我的控制器,
And here's the method I did it with right here,
这是我用的方法,
I just Ctrl dragged from the Refresh Control to this method
我刚从刷新控制Ctrl拖这个方法
called refresh, okay?
称为刷新?
That's all I did to, to make that happen,
这就是我所做的,让这发生,
And inside refresh,
在刷新,
I just called that same method I had before, searchForTweets,
我叫同样的方法之前,searchForTweets,
This one right here, the one that search for tweets,
这一个在这里,一个搜索微博,
And that used to look like this,
这是这个样子,
I only changed one thing in here,
在这里我只改变一件事,
It used to just get the twitterRequest by
过去把twitterRequest
looking at our search term up here,
看着我们的搜索词,
Remember this function?
还记得这个函数吗?
And all I did was added this, which says, if
和我所做的只是增加了这个,说,如果
the lastTwitterRequest has a newer version, then use that,
lastTwitterRequest有新版本,然后使用,
But if it doesn't, then default back to doing to query
但如果没有,那么默认的回做查询
request the way we used to,
要求我们使用的方式,
The only other things that I had to do was turn the refresh
唯一的其他事情,我要做的就是把刷新
control off, you do that with the end refreshing,
控制了,你刷新,
So I just did that when I went back to the main queue here,
所以我就做了,当我回到这里的主要队列,
to get my results, so I turned it off,
我的结果,所以我关闭它,
I also turned it off if for
如果对我也关掉它
some reason I couldn't get any request or whatsoever,
某些原因,我不能得到任何请求或,
Okay, there's nothing in the search term field and
好的,没有什么在搜索领域
I couldn't get a newer version of my last request,
我不能得到一个新版本的我最后的请求,
So I just said, I'm gonna make sure that thing is not
所以我就说,不是我要确保那件事
spinning and spinning forever,
永远旋转和旋转,
They wanna get out of here with that,
他们想离开这里,
And the only other thing I had to do was up here,
唯一的另一件事我要做的就是,
when the search text changes, someone types#Stanford or
当搜索文本变化时,有人#斯坦福或类型
something like that, I need to invalidate that last Twitter
这样,我需要最后一个Twitter失效
request so that it's not trying to get new versions
请求,不是为了得到新版本
of the previous one that I had,
以前的我,
I want it to do the new one,
我想要做新的,
And the way that I made it so that we had these little
和我做了这样的方式我们有这些小
titles right here, see these titles two, three, four, five?
标题在这里,看到这些标题两个,三个,四个,五个?
I implemented another UI table view data source method,
我另一个数据源中方法实现的,
this one down here,
是下面这个,
Called titleForHeaderInSection,
叫titleForHeaderInSection,
I just put titles on the sections,
我把标题部分,
Remember, each section is another pull from Twitter,
记住,每个部分是另一个来自Twitter的拉,
And so I just have each title,
所以我只有每个标题,
It's actually gonna be the count of things I had minus
其实要计数的事情我已经减去
the section number,
节数,
So the top one is section zero,
上面部分是零,
So section zero is gonna show
所以部分会显示为零
the number of pulls that I've made,
拉我的数量,
tweets,count is how many pulls I made,
微博,数量是多少,
And it's obviously gonna
这显然会
decrement as the sections go down,
部分向下递减,
Okay, so that's what gave us this,
好了,这就是给我们,
And you can see that the longer we wait,
你可以看到,我们等待的时间越长,
obviously it pulls more information,
很显然,把更多的信息。
as tweets pile up,
随着微博的堆积,
Okay, let's go back to our slides,
好的,让我们回到我们的幻灯片,
All right, here we go,
好吧,我们开始吧,
So Core Data is this big framework inside of iOS for
这是核心数据iOS的大框架内
doing object-oriented databases,
做面向对象数据库,
So let's talk a little bit about what that means,
让我们讨论一下这意味着什么,
So, when do you need a database?
所以,当你需要一个数据库吗?
Well you need a database when you have a large amount of
你需要一个当你有大量的数据库
data, and especially if you want to kind of make queries
数据,尤其是如果你想查询
into that data and find out things about that data and
到数据,找出数据和事情
the relationships between all the things in there,
之间的关系的所有事情,
You really can't do that by like,
你真的不能通过,
taking a big dictionary or a big array and
大字典或大数组和
searching through it, you need a database,
搜索通过它,你需要一个数据库,
And so there's a lot of technologies for databases out
所以有很多的数据库技术
there but most of them are not object-oriented,
但他们中的大多数并不是面向对象的,
So we have this framework that Apple provides called
所以我们有这个框架,苹果提供了
Core Data, it's what we call an object-oriented database
核心数据,这就是我们所说的一个面向对象的数据库
but actually, it's really not an object-oriented database
但实际上,这真的不是一个面向对象的数据库
on the inside,
在里面,
It's only an object-oriented database on the outside,
这只是一个面向对象的数据库,
The side that you look at,
你看的一面,
Underneath, it's actually a relational database usually,
下面,它实际上是一个关系数据库通常,
Now Core Data is designed to have any backend of storage,
现在核心数据设计有任何后端存储,
But it's primary implementation is on top of
但它的主要实现是最重要的
SQL which is a relational database,
SQL是一种关系数据库,
How many people know what SQL Database is?
有多少人知道什么是SQL数据库吗?
Okay, almost all of you, good,
好吧,几乎所有的你,很好,
So, if we had to do databases in our iOS apps using SQL,
所以,如果我们要做iOS应用程序使用SQL数据库,
we'd be like no, I have to learn this whole query
我们就像不,我必须了解整个查询
language, and how am I gonna do this?
语言,我要怎么做呢?
Not to worry, we don't have to know any SQL to use core Data,
不要担心,我们不需要知道任何SQL使用核心数据,
No SQL whatsoever- we're just gonna purely do this
没有任何SQL——我们要完全做到这一点
on the object side,
在对象方面,
So how does this work?
所以这是如何工作的呢?
How does core Data work?
核心数据是如何工作的呢?
Well, first we're gonna create a visual mapping
首先,我们要创建一个视觉映射
between things in our database and
在我们数据库和之间的事情
some objects that we're gonna be able to program with
一些对象,我们要能够计划
in our object-oriented code that we like,
我们喜欢在我们的面向对象的代码,
And kinda roughly, it's
有点粗略,它
the tables in the database are kinda gonna be objects,
数据库中的表都有点要对象,
And the columns in the tables are kind of vars,
和列在表的var,
But we don't even really care what it's doing there,
但我们甚至不关心它在做什么,
What we're gonna focus on is this visual map,
这是我们要关注的视觉地图,
this visual description basically of our schema,
这种视觉描述基本的模式,
Okay, how many people know what the word schema means?
好的,有多少人知道这个词模式意味着什么吗?
Okay, so two-thirds of you,
好的,所以你的2/3,
So schema is basically the description of what's
所以模式基本上是描述的
in your database, not the contents of it but how all its
在您的数据库,而不是它的内容,但其所有
data types are and how they relate to each other, etc,
数据类型以及它们与对方,等,
So we're gonna do all that graphically,
所以我们要做所有的图形,
And this is what it looks like,
这就是它的样子,
First, if I wanna use Core Data in my app,
首先,如果我想要在我的程序中使用核心数据,
I'm almost certainly going to wanna click this button
我几乎可以肯定会想点击这个按钮
that says Use Core Data,
说使用核心数据,
We've seen it every time we've created an app, and we haven't
我们已经看到它每次我们已经创建了一个应用程序,我们没有
clicked it so far, but now we are going to click it,
点击它到目前为止,但现在我们要点击它,
And clicking Use Core Data there,
点击使用核心数据,
is gonna create two things for us, this visual map,
会为我们创建两个事物,这种视觉地图,
and some code in your App Delegate,
和一些代码在应用程序委托,
And I'm gonna talk about both of those things,
我要谈论这些事情,
Now before I go to the next slide,
在我去下一张幻灯片之前,
notice that the name of this app is CoreDataExample,
请注意,这个应用程序的名称是CoreDataExample,
That's the, just the name of the app that I typed in there,
的,只是应用程序,我输入的名字,
So when I create this app, clicking that
所以当我创建这个应用程序,点击
Use Core Data on, you'll see that it created this file,
使用核心数据,你会发现它创建这个文件,
CoreDataExample,xcdatamodeld,
CoreDataExample xcdatamodeld,
So it chose the name of my app as it,
所以选择了我的程序,因为它的名字,
And this is going to be our data model, all right?
这将是我们的数据模型,对吧?
And so we'll, we'll talk about the AppDelegate
所以我们会,我们会讨论在AppDelegate
code that Use Core Data also generated a little bit later,
代码也使用核心数据生成一点后,
Right now we're gonna focus on this data model file,
现在我们要关注这个数据模型文件,
All right, but before we even do that, what happens if we
好吧,但是在我们即使这样做,如果我们发生了什么
have an existing app and you did not click Use Core Data?
有一个现有的应用程序和你没有点击使用核心数据?
And now you decided, hey, I wanna add core data,
现在你决定,嘿,我想添加核心数据,
Like maybe Smashtag Assignment 5 comes out and
比如Smashtag作业5出来
I tell you to add some Core Data to Smashtag,
我告诉你添加一些Smashtag核心数据,
And you're like, woh, I can't go back and
和你像,哇,我不能回去
click Use Core Data, it's too late,
点击使用核心数据,太晚了,
So you're gonna have to create this data model file
所以你必须创建这个数据模型文件
using new file,
使用新文件,
So you just go to File > New > File like this,
所以你只是去File > New >这样的文件,
You're not gonna pick any of
你不会选择任何
the things we've picked so far,
我们已经选择了到目前为止,
You're gonna scroll down to the section that
你会向下滚动的部分
says Core Data,
核心数据说
And inside there these, there's two things,
里面,有两件事,
Data Model and Mapping Model,
数据模型和映射模型,
And make sure you pick Data Model because that's what you
并确保你选择的数据模型,因为这就是你
want to do here is create your data model,
现在要做的是创建数据模型,
your schema essentially, for your database,
您的数据库模式从本质上讲,,
It's gonna ask you what you wanna call it,
它会问你你想叫它什么,
Now, you don't have to call this the same as the name of
现在,你不需要调用这个一样的名字
your application like Use Core Data button does,
您的应用程序像使用核心数据按钮,
You can call it anything you want,
你可以叫它任何你想要的,
So here, just to be different, I've called it Model,
这里,是不同的,我称它为模型,
it's my model,
这是我的模型,
And by the way,
顺便说一下,
your core data is usually the model of a lot of MVCs,
你的核心数据通常是很多mvc模型,
Okay, a lot of MVCs, their job is going to be to display
好,很多mvc,他们的工作是将会显示
the data in the database, and so this data model is actually
数据库中的数据,所以这些数据模型
the MVC model as well for a lot of MVCs,
MVC模型以及MVC,
So I'll call this one model, and
所以我会打电话给这个模型,
you can see it created model,xedatamodeld,
你可以看到它创建模型、xedatamodeld
So whether you get that file by doing Use Core Data or
所以,不管你被做使用核心数据或文件
whether you get it by creating it yourself,
是否你得到它通过创建它自己,
you're gonna have this mapping file,
你会有一个映射文件,
Now, let me go back to that AppDelegate thing,
现在,让我们回到AppDelegate的事情,
I said they was gonna put some code in your AppDelegate,
我说他们是要把AppDelegate一些代码,
It's very small amount of code,
很少量的代码,
But I wanted to show it to you right here,
但是我想告诉你,
This is what it looks like,
这就是它的样子,
It just creates this one var right here,
它只是创建一个var在这里,
By the way, if you didn't do Use Core Data, of course,
顺便说一下,如果您没有使用核心数据,当然,
you need this code in your AppDelegate,
你需要这个代码AppDelegate,
how are you gonna get it?
你如何得到它?
Just go create some dummy application,
去创造一些虚拟应用程序,
Call it Foo, it doesn't really matter what you call it,
调用Foo,你叫它什么,并不重要
Click Use Core Data when you create it and
当您创建它,点击使用核心数据
then copy this code from that AppDelegate to here,
然后从AppDelegate这段代码复制到这里,
Okay, the code is identical from every app,
好吧,从每一个应用程序的代码是相同的,
The only difference between any of those things is this
这些东西的唯一区别是这样的
one string right here,
一个字符串,
You see that string?
你看到那个字符串?
That's the name of that xcmodeld file, so
这就是xcmodeld文件的名称,所以
datamodeld file,
datamodeld文件,
So with our core data example,
所以,我们的核心数据的例子,
this string would be CoreDataExample,
这个字符串将CoreDataExample,
When we went back and created it on our own with new file,
当我们回去,创建自己的新文件,
of course, we called it Model,
当然,我们称它为模型,
So just make sure this string matches the name of the file,
所以要确保这个字符串匹配的文件的名称,
the xcmodel datamodeld file, okay?
的xcmodel datamodeld文件,好吗?
So that's what you need to do if you didn't do the use
这就是你需要做的如果你没有使用
Code Data originally you are going back and
代码数据最初你会回来
adding it- just copy and paste,
添加-只是复制粘贴,
It's only this one var really, it does provide another thing
只有这一个var真的,它提供了另一件事
in your AppDelegate which is a function called saveContext,
在你AppDelegate一个名为saveContext的函数,
It's a very simple little function,
这是一个非常简单的函数,
I'm gonna show you how you could write it yourself,
我将向您展示如何编写它自己,
If you wanna copy it in, you can,
如果你想复制,你可以,
Also I notice that they have applicationWillTerminate which
我也注意到,他们有applicationWillTerminate哪个
is this application, AppDelegate method,
这个应用程序,AppDelegate方法,
that gets called right before you get terminated or
之前你有终止或调用该方法
you terminate it in any way and they call saveContext,
你以任何方式终止它,他们叫saveContext,
Well, it's a kind of an idea, a good idea,
嗯,这是一种一个想法,一个好主意,
saveContext() just saves your database,
saveContext()只是保存您的数据库,
That's what saveContext does, all right?
这是什么saveContext ?
So this is how you can make up if you didn't do it,
这就是你可以如果你没有这样做,
So anyway, you can see that the only thing in here
总之,在这里你可以看到唯一
is this lazy var persistentContainer, and
这是懒惰的var persistentContainer,
I'm gonna talk all about persistentContainer,
我要所有谈论persistentContainer,
because that's the thing that essentially contains
因为这是本质上的东西
your database, all right?
您的数据库?
But let's go back and talk about the visual map,
但让我们回过头来讨论视觉地图,
Cuz we have to have a visual map before we can do anything
因为我们必须有一个视觉地图之前,我们可以做任何事情
in our database because we have to have some things in
在我们的数据库,因为我们需要一些东西
our database, some objects and things like that,
我们的数据库中,一些对象之类的东西,
And Core database stores things in this kind of very
和核心数据库存储在这种非常
straightforward way,
直接的方法,
It looks very object-oriented in our code because
面向对象的代码,因为它看起来很
in Core Data terms it's storing entities,
在核心数据的存储实体方面,
which look like classes to our code,
像类的代码,
Attributes, which look like vars on our classes,
属性,它看起来像var在我们的类,
And relationship, which just look like vars that point to
和关系,这看起来就像vars指向
other objects in the database, other entities, etc,
数据库中的其他对象,其他实体等,
And so we're gonna use this what I'm calling a storyboard,
所以我们要用这个板我打电话什么,
It's not, don't get confused,
它不是,不感到困惑,
this is not a storyboard, okay?
这不是一个故事板,好吗?
You know what a storyboard is, your Interface Builder thing,
你知道什么是故事板,你的界面构建器的事情,
But it's kind of like a storyboard,
但它就像一个故事板,
that's why it's in quotes for databases,
这就是为什么在引用数据库,
It's a graphical, visual editor to create and
这是一个图形,创建和可视化编辑器
describe all these entities, attributes and relationships,
描述所有这些实体、属性和关系,
okay, that's what we're gonna do here,
好的,这就是我们要做的,
So let's start by adding an entity,
让我们开始通过添加一个实体,
Very easy, we go down to this button on the bottom here
很简单,我们去这个按钮在底部
called Add Entity,
叫添加实体,
Okay, to add an entity,
好了,添加一个实体,
By the way, there's couple other things in that if you
顺便说一下,如果你有其他一些事情
hold down on that button you'll see Add Fetch Request,
按住按钮你会看到添加获取请求,
and Add Configuration,
并添加配置,
I don't have time to talk about those unfortunately,
我没有时间谈论这些不幸的是,
but especially Add Fetch Request is kind of a cool one,
特别是添加获取请求是一种很酷的一个,
So, if you can take what I teach you here and extend it
所以,如果你可以把我在这里教你和扩展它
by going and learning about that, that would be great,
通过学习,那将是伟大的,
So you click Add Entity,
所以你单击Add实体,
it creates a new entity called Entity,
它创建一个新的实体称为实体,
Cuz it doesn't know what name you want for it yet,
因为它不知道什么名字你想要它,
And like I say, this analogous to a class,
就像我说的,这类似于一个类,
Now in our code we're gonna see any instances of this
现在在我们的代码我们要看到任何实例
entity as instances of a class called NSManagedObject,
实体类的实例称为NSManagedObject
So NSManagedObject super important in Core Data,
所以NSManagedObject超级重要的核心数据,
It is the super class or the class of everything that
它是超类或类的东西
comes, all these entities that come out of the database,
来了,所有这些实体的数据库,
It's like the thing that represents them in our code,
就像在我们的代码中代表自己的东西,
and we'll see all about that,
我们会看到,
So for my kind of slides here,
对于我的幻灯片,
what I'm gonna do is create a database that would have
我要做的就是创建一个数据库,
stuff like we got from Twitter,
我们从Twitter、
So it's gonna have tweets and
所以它会有推特和
we're gonna have Twitter users,
我们要有Twitter用户,
So those are gonna be two entities that we have and
这些都是要我们有两个实体
you're gonna see eventually, we're gonna have Tweet and
你会看到最后,我们要推
TwitterUser classes in our code and
在我们的代码和TwitterUser类
we're gonna access vars and all that stuff,
我们要访问var和所有的东西,
So I'm gonna rename this entity,
所以我要重命名这个实体,
this, that I added that was defaulted to entity,
这个,我还说,违约的实体,
I'm gonna rename it and call it Tweet,
我要重命名,称之为微博,
So this is gonna be the first entity that I'm creating
这是第一个我在创建实体
in the database,
在数据库中,
Now, an entity can have attributes,
现在,一个实体可以有属性,
Those are kind of like vars, and relationships,
这些都是有点像var,关系,
Those are like vars that point to other entities,
那些像var指向其他实体,
And I told you this fetched properties down at the bottom,
我告诉过你这获取属性在底部,
I'm not gonna talk about,
我不会讲,
Very cool, but not gonna talk about them,
很酷,但不会谈论他们,
Not just time-wise,
不仅仅是时间,
So let's go and add some attributes to this entity,
所以让我们去添加一些属性的实体,
Real easy, you click this plus button,
真正的轻松,你点击这个加号按钮,
there's also an Add Attribute button,
还有一个按钮,添加属性
see it down in the lower right hand corner there,
看到它的右下角,
But I'm gonna click this little plus
但是我点击这个小+
button right there under the section called Attributes,
按钮属性章节下,
And when I do there it adds a new attribute called attribute
当我做它添加一个新的属性称为属性
and I'm gonna edit its name directly,
我要直接编辑它的名字,
just like I did the entity name,
就像我做的实体名称,
I'm gonna change this to be text,
我要改变这个文本,
So, this is gonna be our tweet text, the 140 characters
所以,这将是我们的推文,140个字符
of the tweet is gonna be this particular attribute,
的推特是这个特殊的属性,
Now, notice as soon as I did that, I got an error,
现在,请注意当我这么做的时候,我得到了一个错误,
In the corner there, this red error,
在角落里,这个红色的错误,
And the reason for
的原因
that is all attributes have to have a type,
这是所有属性必须有一个类型,
They can't just be undefined type like this one is,
他们不能只是这样的未定义的类型,
You see where it says the type is undefined,
你知道它是未定义的类型,说
So, we need to change that to be a type,
所以,我们需要改变类型,
And it's really easy, right there where it says undefined,
很简单,在这里表示未定义,
We're just going to mouse down,
我们将鼠标向下,
it's gonna bring up a menu and we can choose our type,
它会弹出一个菜单,我们可以选择类型,
Now, these are the types we have to choose from,
现在,这些都是我们必须选择类型,
A lot of different numeric types like 16-bit integers,
很多不同的数值类型像16位整数,
32-bit integer, etc,
32位整数,等等,
Doubles, floats, can a be string of course,
双打,漂浮,当然可以是字符串,
a Boolean value, a date which is going to look like a date,
一个布尔值,一个看起来像一个日期,日期
you know, the date struct in our code,
你知道,日期在我们的代码结构,
And binary data which is gonna look like the data struct
和二进制数据是数据结构
inside our code,
在我们的代码,
So, these are gonna map to very familiar data types
因此,这些会映射到非常熟悉数据类型
that we see,
我们看到,
There is that one at the bottom there,
有一个在底部,
transformable, another thing I'm not gonna talk about,
可变形的,另一件我不会谈论,
But transformable allows you to store anything
但可变形的允许您存储任何东西
into the database by converting it to a data, and
将它转换为一个数据到数据库中,和
then converting it back on the way out,
然后把它回来的路上,
And so if you pick transformable there,
所以如果你选择可变形的,
you're gonna have to do some extra work,
你需要做一些额外的工作,
To tell Core Data about that transformation, and that's why
告诉核心数据转换,这就是原因
I don't really have time to tell you about, but just know
我真的没有时间告诉你,只是知道
that if you wanted to store something like a CGRect,
如果你想储存CGRect中,
Actually, if I was going to store a CGRect, I might use
事实上,如果我要商店CGRect中,我可能会使用
the function, there's some function called something like
功能,有一些函数类似
NSStringFromCGRect,
It gives you a string, and
它给你一个字符串,和
then there's NSCGRectFromString or
还有NSCGRectFromString或
something like that,
类似的,
So I'd probably store it as a string,
所以,我可能会将其存储为字符串,
but if I had something more complicated than that,
但如果我有比这更复杂的东西,
then I might use a transformable,
然后我可能使用一个可变化的,
All right, these attributes here are going to be accessed,
好吧,这些属性将被访问,
we're gonna get and set their values,
我们要获取和设置值,
Well actually, we're not going to do this but fundamentally
实际上,我们不会这样做,但从根本上
the way you do it is you have these two methods,
你是这两种方法,
value(forKey) and setValue (forKey),
值(forKey)和setValue(forKey),
And I'll talk about how we're gonna use that, but
和我将讨论我们如何使用,但是
that's how we're gonna set and get the values on an entity,
这就是我们要设置和获取的值在一个实体,
Notice the error went away as soon as we
我们注意到错误就走了
gave this thing, a type,
给了这个东西,一个类型,
So here I'm gonna add some more attributes, identifier,
这里我要添加更多属性,标识符,
which is just some string that identifies the tweet and
这只是一些字符串标识和推特
then created, which was when it was tweeted,
然后创建,推时,
Notice I'm setting created's type here to be date because
注意到我在这里设置的类型创建日期,因为
it is a date, obviously, when the thing was created,
这是一个日期,显然,当创建的,
Now this is one way to look at our entities and attributes,
现在这是一个方法来看看我们的实体和属性,
this kind of table form,
这种表的形式,
But we can actually look at it in graphical form as well,
但我们可以看看它以图形化的形式,
If you see down in the corner where it says editor style,
如果你看到在角落编辑风格,
If I click on the other button there,
如果我点击其他按钮,
the one that looks a little more like a graph,
一个看起来更像一个图,
then it shows me the same thing but
然后它向我展示了同样的事情
in this graphical form,
在这个图形的形式,
It's even on graph paper, all right?
即使在坐标纸,好吗?
And in this form right here we can do
我们能做在这里的形式
all the things that we did in the other one,
所有我们在另一个,
For example, I can still add entity here,
例如,我仍然可以添加实体,
So I'm gonna add another entity for my Twitter User,
所以我要为我的Twitter用户,添加另一个实体
this is people who tweet,
这是微博的人,
And there it is, it called it entity again,
在这里,它又称它为实体,
that's the default,
这是默认的,
We'll set its name to be TwitterUser,
我们将设置它的名字TwitterUser,
All right, so we now have two entities, you see on there,
好了,现在我们有两个实体,你看,
What's kinda cool is as you drag these entities around,
酷的是当你拖动这些实体,
this, this kind of editor, this graphical
这种编辑器,这个图形
editor, will automatically kind of keep them spaced apart
编辑器中,将自动保持间隔分开
from each other,
从对方,
Which is kind of fun, especially since they're going
这是很有趣的,特别是因为他们吗
to start having wires connecting them because
因为开始有电线连接它们
they're going to start having relationships
他们将开始有关系
to each other as you're going to see in a moment,
对方为你会看到在一个时刻,
We can add attributes in this graphical style as well- you
我们可以添加属性在这个图形风格——你
can edit those right in there just by double clicking on
可以编辑这些在那里只要双击吗
them, change whatever you want,
改变任何你想要的,
So, here I got a screenName, now of course I got an error
所以,在这里,我有一个屏幕名,当然我有一个错误
again because I didn't set the type of that screenName,
因为我没有设置类型的屏幕名,
So, in this view you set the types by bringing up
所以,在这个视图中设置类型抚养
the inspector,
检查员,
So you just bring up your normal inspector,
所以你只要把你的正常的检查员,
attribute inspector,
属性检查器,
And the, here you can see it's inspecting screenName,
这里的,你可以看到它的检查屏幕名,
it's got the name there,
它的名字,
There's some other things in here like transient,
有一些其他的事情在这里像瞬态,
indexed, optional,
索引,可选的,
By the way, that optional doesn't mean this is optional
可选的方式,并不意味着这是可选的
like the Swift thing optional,
喜欢快速的可选的,
This is optional like in SQL database terms, right,
这是可选的像SQL数据库而言,正确的,
In relational database optional,
在关系数据库中可选的,
So I'm not gonna talk about any of the database
所以我不会谈论任何数据库
You rarely need to set any of these properties right here,
你很少需要设置这些属性,
stuff of it,
的东西,
But you do need to set the type,
但你需要设置类型,
So we're not gonna talk about that, but
所以我们不会谈论,但是
we have to set the type right here,
我们必须设置类型,
And the screenName, of course, is a string,
和屏幕名,当然,是一个字符串,
So I'm just gonna change it to a string,
所以我要将其更改为一个字符串,
I'm adding another attribute to the TwitterUser,
我向TwitterUser添加另一个属性,
this one is the name, the person's actual name,
这个是名字,人的实际名称,
not their @ sign handle, but their actual name,
不是他们的@符号处理,但他们的实际名称,
Now we've built a couple of entities with a bunch of
现在我们已经建立了两个实体与一群
attributes on them, okay, and this is gonna look like
属性,好吧,这是会是什么样子
classes with vars in our code eventually,
类与var最终我们的代码,
But what about relationships, obviously a Tweet and
但是关系,显然一条微博
a TwitterUser have a relationship to each other,
TwitterUser有关系,
And to create relationships between things we just
和创造的事情我们之间的关系
Ctrl+drag, this is our favorite gesture in Xcode and
Ctrl +拖,这是我们最喜欢的手势在Xcode中,
we're using it again,
我们使用一遍,
Ctrl+drag to create a relationship
Ctrl +拖动创建一个关系
between two things,
两件事之间,
And it actually doesn't matter which direction you Ctrl+drag,
其实无所谓哪个方向你Ctrl +拖,
because you're creating kind of a bidirectional
因为你创造一种双向的
relationship,
的关系,
So here, I did Ctrl+drag, and it automatically created this
这里,我做了Ctrl +拖,自动创建
relationship, which it called newRelationship on both sides,
双方的关系,它叫做newRelationship,
And this relationship is essentially just gonna be
和这种关系本质上是会
a var in our class,
我们班上一个var,
But the var's type is either going to be the type, if it's
但var的类型是类型,如果是
like a Tweet, you know, it's gonna be a single one, or
像一个Tweet,你知道,它会是一个,或者
it could be an NSSet, if it's many of them,
可能是NSSet,如果是他们中的许多人,
Like a Twitter user might have many tweets, and
像一个Twitter用户可能有很多微博,和
I'll talk about that in a moment,
我一会儿会讲到,
So, from a Tweet's perspective this relationship to
所以,从微博的角度来看这种关系
a TwitterUser is the Tweeter,
TwitterUser是推特,
The person who tweeted this tweet,
发推特的人,
So, I'm going to change the name of this relationship on
所以,我要改变这种关系的名称
the Tweet side to be tweeter instead of newRelationship,
推特,而不是newRelationship推一边,
which was the default,
这是默认的,
But, on the other, okay, so that's why I call it tweeter,
但是,另一方面,好的,这就是为什么我叫它推特,
On the other side the TwitterUser from its
另一方面从其TwitterUser
perspective though, okay, the relationship of the tweet is
不过,角度好,推特的关系
the tweets that this Twitter user has tweeted,
的微博推特用户写道:,
Okay, it's not tweeter, the Twitter user is the tweeter,
好吧,这不是推特,推特用户的推特,
so he would never call this relationship tweeter,
所以他永远不会叫这个关系来说,
He's gonna call this relationship tweets
他会调用这个tweet的关系
because this is the tweet,
因为这是一条推特,
Now notice that's plural, okay,
现在注意到复数,
we'll talk about that in a second,
我们会讲到,
Notice that when we do this, Xcode tracks if I'm inspecting
请注意,当我们这样做时,Xcode跟踪如果我检查
the tweet's relationship there on the TwitterUser side,
推特的关系在TwitterUser方面,
it knows the inverse,
它知道逆,
It knows that tweeter goes the opposite direction,
它知道推特走相反的方向,
there's always gonna be an inverse relationship,
总是有会成反比关系,
So let's talk about that tweets being a plural right?
所以让我们来谈谈微博是一个复数?
So a tweet can only have one tweeter,
所以只能有一个推特,推特
Only one person can have tweeted it, but
只有一个人可以推,但是
a Twitter user can tweet thousands of tweets, okay?
Twitter用户可以推成千上万的微博,好吗?
And so that's a little different
这有点不同
kind of relationship,
的关系,
So how do we specify that?
那么我们如何指定吗?
We call the tweets relationship the,
我们所说的推文的关系,
a to many relationship because obviously the Twitter
因为许多关系显然Twitter
user can have many tweets,
用户可以有很多微博,
So that's called to many in database parlance, and
这是许多数据库的说法,和
you set that right in the Inspector,
您设置的检查员,
So you just click on that tweets and
所以你只需点击微博
you go over here to where it says Type,
你去这里,类型,
and instead of having it be To One you're gonna change it
相反的它是一个你会改变它
to be To Many, okay, so now it's a to many relationship,
对许多人来说,好的,现在许多的关系,这是一个
Right there, you can see that it's changed a little bit as,
在这里,你可以看到它的改变了一点,
and we'll show that in a second,
我们会显示在第二个,
But the type of this relationship now on the tweet
但现在这种关系的类型在推特上
side is still type NSManagedObject,
方仍NSManagedObject类型,
because it points to another entity in the database,
因为它指向另一个实体在数据库中,
And we know that the objects in the database
我们知道,数据库中的对象
are represented by an NSManagedObject,
由一个NSManagedObject,
So that's gonna be the type of that var,
这是将var的类型,
Although we're eventually gonna make it even better than
虽然我们最终会使它甚至比
that, but on the other side though,
,但另一方面,
the type of that var is NSSet of NSManagedObject, okay?
var是NSSet NSManagedObject的的类型,对吧?
Now NSSet, there is a Swift struct called set,
现在NSSet,迅速结构被称为集,
It's a generic type, it's just like an array where you have
这是一个泛型类型,就像一个数组中
to say what's in an array,
说什么一个数组,
same thing with a set you have to say what's in it,
同样一套你说什么,
NSSet is kind of an older Objective-C kind of set,
NSSet objective - c是一种老的,
It's not generic, it's untyped,
它不是通用的,它是无类型,
The things in NSSet are any, which we kinda need a little
NSSet任何的事情,我们需要一点
bit here cuz we really don't know what kinds of things
在这里因为我们真的不知道什么样的事情
are in there,
在那里,
However, in your code you can cast from this NSSet
然而,在您的代码可以从这个NSSet
of NSManagedObject to a set of what you know to be in there
NSManagedObject一组你知道在那里
using as question mark, and
使用问号,
if that in fact is what's in there, it will work,
如果,事实上就是在那里,它会工作,
So that's the NSSet there,
这就是NSSet那里,
One last thing I'm gonna show you here before
最后一件事我要告诉你这里之前
we get back to the slides is this Delete Rule,
这是我们回到幻灯片删除规则,
You see the delete rule on the,
你看到删除的规则,
clicked on tweets on here so we're inspecting tweets,
点击微博在这里我们检查微博,
And this delete rule tells you what happens
这个删除规则告诉你发生了什么
to the pointed-to tweets if we deleted this Twitter user,
指针微博如果我们删除这个Twitter用户,
Cuz if I delete this Twitter user,
因为如果我删除这个Twitter用户,
does that mean I delete all of the Twitter user's tweets?
这是否意味着我删除所有的Twitter用户的推文?
Well, it depends on this delete rule right here,
嗯,这取决于这个删除规则,
this delete rule is saying nullify, which would mean no,
这个删除规则说取消,这意味着没有,
So right now,
现在,
Those tweets would stay in the database, and their tweeter
这些tweet留在数据库中,和他们的推特
will be set to nil because their tweeter got deleted,
将被设置为零,因为他们的推特被删除,
But there is a cascading delete rule, which would say
但有一个级联删除规则,会说
if I delete this thing then delete everything that it
如果我删除这个东西然后删除一切
points to, just go right down the graph and
点,就图和
delete everything,
删除一切,
So that's what controls what happens when you delete,
这就是控制当你删除,
Now I'm not gonna ask you to even do delete;
甚至现在我不会要求你做删除;
I guess I might ask you an extra credit to do delete in
我想我可能会问你一个额外的信用做删除
assignment five,
作业五,
Because deletion kinda- you're really gonna know what
因为删除——你会知道
you're doing- when you can delete things, and
你在做什么,当你可以删除东西,和
what kind of delete rules you want,
你想要什么样的删除规则,
But I just want to let you know that you specify
但我只是想让你知道你指定
the delete rule right here in the inspector,
删除规则检查员,
Okay, now that you've defined all your entities, attributes
好吧,既然你已经定义了所有的实体、属性
in relationships, then what can we do with these things?
与这些关系,那么我们能做些什么事情?
Well to do anything with it we need to get a hold of them
我们用它来做任何事情需要控制住它们
in our code, grab onto them basically, and
在我们的代码中,抓住他们基本上,
to do that we need another important class,
要做到这一点,我们需要另一个重要的类,
NSManagedObjectContext, so I told you
NSManagedObjectContext,所以我告诉你
all those things in the database are NSManagedObjects,
nsmanagedobject数据库中的所有这些事情,
you need an NSManagedObjectContext,
你需要一个NSManagedObjectContext,
which represents a database to do anything with them,
代表一个数据库做任何事,
to get any of them, to create any of them, etc,
其中任何一个,创建的,等等,
this is the hub around which Core Data activity turns,
这是核心数据的中心活动,
as I say there,
就像我说的,
So how do I get one of these NSManagedObjectContext?
所以我怎么得到这些NSManagedObjectContext之一?
And the answer is, you need a persistentContainer,
答案是,你需要一个persistentContainer,
Woo-hoo, and you know where to get one of those,
啊,你知道的,
You just click, Use Core Data, and
你点击,使用核心数据,
it's gonna appear in your AppDelegate,
它会出现在你AppDelegate,
You're gonna get that lazy var,
你会得到,懒惰的var,
that's called persistentContainer,
这叫做persistentContainer,
And that is gonna be a persistentContainer,
这将是一个persistentContainer,
And from that you can get the context,
从那你可以得到的背景下,
Now, if you have the lazy var in your AppDelegate,
现在,如果你有懒惰AppDelegate var,
How the heck do you call that var?
你叫var到底如何?
How do you get that var?
你怎么得到var ?
And this is how you do it, okay?
这是你怎么做,好吗?
You get a copy of the shared UIApplication, now,
你拿到一份UIApplication共享,现在,
we didn't talk about this but your app has this one and
我们不谈论这个但是你的应用
only UIApplication object that represents your application
只有UIApplication对象代表您的应用程序
and you get it by doing UIApplication,shared,
你UIApplication得到通过,共享,
it's a var,
这是一个var,
Static var in UIApplication class,
UIApplication类中的静态变量,
Gives you the shared one,
给你共享一个,
Then you're gonna access this var in UIApplication which is
然后你要访问这UIApplication var在
its delegate,
其委托,
Now, its delegate is automatically set up for
现在,它的代表是自动设置
you to be this Swift class AppDelegate that you see
你这个迅速类AppDelegate你看到
always; we always put it off in Supporting Files and
总是,我们总是把它在支持文件,
get it out of our way, but it's created for you,
把它从我们的方式,但它是为你创建的,
it's a nice little class,
这是一个很好的小类,
We're going to talk about the application life cycle, and
我们将讨论应用程序生命周期,和
where it fits in, in a little bit, but for now all
它适合在一点,但是现在呢
you need to know is you can get AppDelegate, and you want
你需要知道的是你可以得到AppDelegate,和你想要的
to send persistentContainer to it to get that var, but of
向它发送persistentContainer var,但是
course you have to as it to be the AppDelegate class first,
当然你必须首先在AppDelegate类,
So this is the code you're going to use,
这是你要使用的代码,
(UIApplication,shared,delegate as!
(UIApplication,共享,委托!
AppDelegate) All that in one expression
AppDelegate)在一个表达式
dot persistentContainer now you're gonna get this
点persistentContainer现在你会得到这个
persistentContainer, and notice I'm doing as
persistentContainer,注意到我所做的
exclamation point this will crash if my App Delegate is
感叹号崩溃如果我的应用程序委托
not in fact App Delegate, but it's already wired up
不实际上应用程序委托,但它已经连接起来
to be that for you when you create a new project,
为您,当您创建一个新项目,
so that should never be a problem,
所以不应该成为一个问题,
Okay? So
好吧?
now I have this persistentContainer,
现在我有这个persistentContainer,
I need to get the context out of it,
我需要的上下文,
And, so,
所以,
the container has an awesome var called viewContext,
容器有一个很棒的var称为viewContext,
And the viewContext is an NSManagedObjectContext that's
和viewContext NSManagedObjectContext就是
only suitable for use on the main queue,
只适合用在主要的队列,
This is in red,
这是红色的,
you know whenever you see anything in red on my slides,
你知道每当你看到任何红色的幻灯片,
this means pay attention, it will matter for
这意味着关注,将物质
your homework, and in life, but
你的家庭作业,在生活中,但是
you can only use this viewContext in the main queue,
你只能用这个viewContext在主队列,
it called viewContext because you use it with your views,
这叫viewContext因为你使用它与你的观点,
okay, your UI views, that's why we call it viewContext,
好的,UI视图,这就是为什么我们称之为viewContext,
So why do I make a point about this main queue?
为什么我对这个主要强调队列?
Well, the reason I do that is because NSManagedObjectContext
好吧,我之所以这么做是因为NSManagedObjectContext
is not thread-safe,
不是线程安全的,
But I'm gonna talk you, talk to you about how we can do
但是我要告诉你,和你谈谈我们如何做
multithreaded database stuff towards the end of this talk,
多线程数据库的东西在这个演讲,
All right, so now you have this viewContext then you can
好了,现在你有了这个viewContext然后你可以
use it to do things,
用它来做事情,
Now, it's so
现在,就是这样的
{UIApplication,shared,delegate as!
UIApplication {、共享,委托!
Appdelegate),persistentContai- ner,
Appdelegate),persistentContai -尼珥,
that's kind of a messy line of code,
这是一个混乱的代码,
There's a lot of, there's as and all these things in there,
有很多,和所有这些事情,
So at times we'll just create a static version of
所以有时我们会创建一个静态的版本
persistentContainer in our AppDelegate,
persistentContainer AppDelegate,
Okay, we'll just call it the same thing,
好吧,我们就叫它同样的事情,
persistentContainer but it's static and
persistentContainer但静态和
it's just gonna return that messy line of code,
它会返回,混乱的代码,
So now we can get that persistentContainer with
所以现在我们可以得到persistentContainer
AppDelegate,persistentContai- ner,
AppDelegate persistentContai——尼珥,
See what I did there?
看看我在做什么吗?
I just made it easier to get up by making that be a static,
我做到了容易通过,是一个静态的,
a class var, and we can do the same thing with viewContext,
一个类变量,我们可以用viewContext做同样的事情,
you might create a static called viewContext and for
您可以创建一个静态viewContext和呼吁
the rest of these slides you can assume I've done this,
剩下的这些幻灯片你可以假设我做这个,
Which is good because typing that long messy thing would
这很好,因为打字脏乱不堪的事情
make all my slides spill over the edge,
让我所有的幻灯片溢出的边缘,
So I'm gonna use this shorter version as well,
所以我要用这个短的版本,
And you're welcome to create the static
和欢迎你来创建静态的
version in your AppDelegate if you want
版本在你AppDelegate如果你想要的
to make your code a little cleaner,
让你的代码更干净一点,
Now this viewContext in the persistentContainer
现在这个viewContext persistentContainer
There's one of them that represents your entire
有其中一个代表你的全部
are shared,
是共享的,
database,
数据库,
So it's perfectly fine to create a single static
所以完全可以创建一个静态的
that does this,
做这个,
By the way, what if you wanted multiple databases?
顺便说一下,如果你想要多个数据库呢?
You could even have multiple databases with
你甚至可以有多个数据库
different schema,
不同的模式,
Very easy, if you go look at the code for
很简单,如果你去看看代码
persistentContainer in AppDelegate,
persistentContainer AppDelegate,
you'll see it's only like four lines of code,
你会看到只有四行代码,
And you could just copy it to create a different
你可以复制它创建一个不同的
persistentContainer using a different xcmodeld file,
使用不同的xcmodeld persistentContainer文件,
Instead of using model according to the example,
根据这个例子中,而不是使用模型
create another one with a different one and
创建另一个与另一个
you can just go file, new file and create another data model,
你可以去文件,新文件并创建另一个数据模型,
You could even create two persistent containers with
你甚至可以创建两个持久性容器
the same model,
相同的模型,
So they would be separate databases, but
所以他们会单独的数据库,但是
have the same model, the same entities to that and
有相同的模式,相同的实体,
the same relationship to that,
相同的关系,
It's perfectly allowed as well,
这是完全允许的,
But for everything you're going to do in this class, and
但是对于你要做的每件事都在这个类中,和
for really with most apps,
对于真正与大多数应用程序,
you're going to have one big database,
你将会有一个大的数据库,
And you're going to have this one persistent container that
和你要这一个持久的容器
is the container for it,
是它的容器,
All right,
好吧,
So now I have a context in my hand, this viewContext,
现在我手中有一个上下文,这viewContext,
And what can I do?
我能做什么?
Well, of course, I can insert objects into the database,
当然,我可以将对象插入到数据库,
I can delete objects from the database,
我可以从数据库中删除对象,
And I can query for objects in the database,
我可以查询数据库中的对象,
So, let's talk about all those things,
所以,让我们来谈谈那些东西,
Let's start with insert because until we insert some
让我们从插入开始因为直到我们插入一些
data in the database we can't do any of those other things,
数据库中的数据我们不能做任何其他的事情,
And the way you insert an object in the database, or
你在数据库中插入一个对象,或
a way to do it, and actually for
一个方法,实际上
the next few slide I'm going to kind of show you the,
接下来的几张我要给你们看,
the essentials,
生活必需品,
But, we're eventually going to move up to a high level and
但是,我们最终会上升到一个高水平
access this stuff in a much nicer way,
访问这个东西好得多的方式,
But I'll tell you the basics of it first,
但我要告诉你的基本知识,
So the basic way to put something in the database is
所以把东西放在数据库的基本方法
with this really interesting method,
这个非常有趣的方法,
NSEntityDescription,insertNew- Object(forEntityName: into:
NSEntityDescription insertNew——对象(forEntityName:到:
context),
Okay, that's a mouthful, used to be even more of a mouthful
好了,这就是一口,更多的一口
before they renamed it,
他们改了之前,
And you just specify the name of the entity, so
你只是指定实体的名称,所以
Tweet or TwitterUser,
推特或TwitterUser,
And you give it a context that is gonna be the viewContext
你给它一个上下文是viewContext
you got from the AppDelegate,
你有在AppDelegate,
And boom, it's gonna create one of these in the database,
和繁荣,它会创建一个在数据库中,
Now all of its attributes will be nil,
现在它的所有属性将是零,
Okay, although you can inspect the attributes in
好吧,虽然你可以检查属性
the data model editor and specify default value,
数据模型编辑器和指定默认值,
And so it might start out with the default value,
所以它可能从默认值,
But if it doesn't, then they'll start out as nil,
但如果没有,那么他们就会开始是零,
Okay, so that's great,
好了,这很好,
I can now create one,
我现在可以创建一个,
And now I need to set those vars to have some value,
现在我需要设置这些增值有价值,
I need to set the text of the tweet and things like that and
我需要设置的文本推特之类的东西
I told you I'm gonna do this with value for key and
我告诉你我要做的这个键和值
set value for key,
为关键的设置值,
So for example I wanted to set the let's say the text,
比如我想设置的文本,
I could just say tweet,
我可以只说推特,
A set value for key quote text, to be a string,
一组值的键引用文本,是一个字符串,
And you can do dot notation here, with value for key path,
你可以在这里做点符号,为关键路径与价值,
That's what I'm showing in green right there,
这就是我用绿色显示,
You can have, if you had a tweet you can actually set
你可以,如果你有一个你可以设置
the tweet's tweeter's name, using this dot notation to set
推特的推特的名字,使用这个点符号
value for key path tweeter dot name and it would go through
价值关键路径名称和它会通过推特点
the tweeter relationship which is kinda fun,
推特的关系有点有趣,
I'm kinda going fast through this because this is a really
我有点快通过这个因为这是真的
terrible API,
可怕的API,
First of all it's got any in there so
首先它有任何在那里
there's not type checking going on here, okay?
没有类型检查,好吗?
You could say, set value date for key quote text, all right?
你可能会说,设置值的日期键引用文本,对吧?
And that would be perfectly accepted by Swift,
这将是完全被迅速接受,
Date is an Any and quote text is a String, but
日期是一个任何引用的文本是一个字符串,但是
of course that's gonna fail miserably at run time, okay,
当然,会在运行时失败,好吧,
because the text is a Atring,
因为文本是atr,
So we're not really gonna use this API but this is
所以我们不使用这个API,但这是
the underlying basic way that Core Data is doing this,
底层核心数据的基本方式是这样做,
Yes the key is just the name of the attribute, and
是的,关键是属性的名称,以及
the value is all the things we've talked about before,
价值是我们之前谈论的所有事情,
I do have the blue Use Scalar Type there which
我有蓝色的使用标量类型
is interesting,
很有趣,
If the thing you're putting in the database is a flow or
如果你把数据库中是一个流或
an Int32 or one of these things,
Int32或其中的一个东西,
It's actually gonna be stored in a database as an NSNumber,
它实际上会作为NSNumber存储在数据库中,
which is a class,
这是一个类,
it's an object, kind of generic holder of numbers,
这是一个对象,通用的数字,
But if you flip on the switch in the inspector in your data
但是如果你打开开关检查员在您的数据
modeller for that attribute saying use a scalar type,
分析员说使用一个标量类型属性,
then it'll make the type be double or int or whatever,
然后它会让双或int类型等等,
instead of NSNumber, so,
而不是NSNumber,所以,
I know, you had a question?
我知道,你有问题吗?
>> Yes, so the question is, does set value reject
> >是啊,问题是,拒绝并设置值
something where the types don't match?
类型不匹配的地方吗?
And the answer is, it can't,
答案是,它不能,
It doesn't know the type, the types are any,
它不知道类型,类型是什么
as long as it matches any- and everything matches any,
只要它匹配任何匹配任何的一切,
So, it can't,
所以,它不能,
There's no way for it to have enough information to reject,
没有办法拒绝的它有足够的信息,
As long as it matches any, it'll accept that as the type,
只要它匹配任何,它会接受的类型,
And then at runtime, it will crash,
然后在运行时,它会崩溃,
If you try to set a date to be into a string field,
如果你尝试设定一个日期字符串字段,
>> So when it's like [INAUDIBLE]
> >当它就像(听不清)
save context,
拯救环境,
do you have to like make it go through,
你有喜欢让它通过,
Or is it, >> Go and remove,
还是,> >去删除
>> [CROSSTALK] >> What do you
> >[CROSSTALK]> >你的
mean go and remove it?
意思是去删除它?
Remove what?
删除什么?
Yeah, we'll talk about saving in this,
是的,我们会讲节约,
So, the question is,
所以,问题是,
when the app terminates it does save context and
在应用程序终止时保存上下文和
they're trying to save this, we'll talk all about saving in
他们试图保存,我们将谈论所有储蓄
a minute cause that's an important piece of this,
一分钟的这是一个重要的原因,
That's the keys and values, pretty straightforward there;
键和值,很简单;
in fact we're going to talk about saving right now,
事实上我们现在要讲的储蓄,
We do a nice lead in,
我们做一个好领导,
All these changes that you make with that set value even
所有这些变化,甚至设置值
insert entity description for
插入实体描述
entity name context whatever that thing is called,
实体名称上下文的任何事情,
All that stuff only happens in memory,
所有这些只发生在内存中,
if you want that to actually happen permanently in
如果你想真正发生永久
the database you need to save it,
数据库需要保存它,
And you do that by telling the context,
你这样做,告诉上下文,
like that view context thing, to save with the method save,
这样的视图上下文,保存方法保存,
It couldn't be simpler, except that it can throw,
不可能是简单的,除了可以扔,
Save is a method that can throw because
节约是一个方法,可以把因为
maybe there's a problem writing out to the database,
也许有一个问题写数据库,
And there's many problems that could happen writing
还有许多问题可能发生的写作
out to the database,
数据库,
And you need to look at documentation and
你需要看文档和
kind of figure out what they all are,
算出的都是什么,
But the take home message here is you do need to save,
但这里的带回家的信息是你需要保存,
If you don't save, that substance is gonna be lost
如果你不救,物质会丢失
when your app exists or whatever,
当你的应用存在之类的,
So you definitely just save,
所以你肯定只是保存,
And especially when talking about multithreaded Core Data,
特别是在谈到多线程的核心数据,
And one thread is working,
和一线工作时,
That thread needs to save if it wants any of the other
该线程需要拯救如果它希望的任何其他
threads to see the work that it's done,
线程看到工作的完成,
Okay, so you can use try question mark here, remember,
好的,那么你可以使用问号,记住,
which means try and
这意味着试着
if it fails, just return nil and ignore it,
如果失败了,就返回nil,忽略它,
You can do that, if you don't mind that it didn't save,
你可以这样做,如果你不介意的话,它没有保存,
And the kinda things that can happen, saving errors,
和有点事情发生,保存错误,
You could obviously have file system problems,
你可以很明显有文件系统问题,
your disk is full or something like that,
磁盘已满或类似的东西,
But you can also have inconsistencies in
但是你也可以不一致
the database, maybe you had conflicting
数据库中,也许你有冲突
data of two threads trying to save to the same database, and
数据的两个线程试图保存到同一个数据库,和
they've tried to write over the top of each other,
他们想写的,
those kind of things,
这样的事情,
Again, a lot of those problems you're not gonna have,
再次,很多这些问题你不会有,
unless you build a pretty complicated,
除非你建立一个相当复杂,
multithreaded application, or something like that,
多线程应用程序,或类似的东西,
but, again, you gotta check the documentation, I couldn't,
但是,你必须检查文档,我不能,
it would take too long for me to go through all of it,
需要太长时间我经历的所有,
Okay now, as I said value forKey and setValue forKey,
好,正如我所说的价值forKey setValue forKey,
Really ugly,
真的很丑,
What we really want to do is be able to set these vars
我们真正要做的是能够设置这些增值
as vars, we just wanna have a var called text
作为增值,我们只是想有一个var叫文本
somewhere that we can set,
我们可以设置的地方,
And of course we're exactly going to do that,
当然,我们到底要这样做,
And the way we're going to do that is create a subclass of
和我们要做的是创建一个子类
NSManagedObject, instead of having NSManagedObject in
NSManagedObject,而不是NSManagedObject
the database we doing set-value, get-value on it,
我们的数据库做设定值,能创造更多的价值,
Instead we're going to create a subclass of NSManageObjects
相反我们要创建NSManageObjects的一个子类
and it's going to have vars on there for all the attributes,
它会在那里var属性,
like text, and screen name and all those things,
喜欢文字,屏幕名称和所有这些事情,
And Xcode will generate all that code for
和Xcode将生成代码
you behind the scenes,
你在幕后,
you don't have to do any work to make that happen,
你不需要做任何工作要做到这一点,
Quite quite simple, so let's look and see how we do that,
很简单,让我们看看我们如何做到这一点,
You do that by inspecting the entity,
你通过检查实体,
So here I've chosen tweet,
这里我选择了微博,
Okay, not any of its attributes but
好吧,但不是它的任何属性
tweet itself, and I want to make it so
tweet本身,我想让它如此
it generates this magic code, and how do I do that?
它生成这个神奇的代码,我该怎么做?
Well, if you go down on the inspector
好吧,如果你去检查
a little ways you see it says Codegen,
你看到它说Codegen一点方法,
See that Codegen, that's for
看到Codegen,
generating this code, this magic code,
生成此代码,这个神奇的代码,
Now, you actually have a couple of choices here for
现在,你在这里有两个选择
the Codegen,
Codegen,
The default I believe is this one Class Definition,
默认我相信这是一个类的定义,
If you choose this one it will generate that subclass for
如果你选择这个会生成子类
you and it will just work,
你只会工作,
Okay, you'll be able to access your tweets as a class
好的,你可以访问你的微博作为一个类
called tweet,
推特,
With all the vars,
所有的var,
Now this sounds good and
现在,这听起来不错
it is good; by the way if you do this class definition
它是好的,如果你做这类定义
codegen it will not show up in your navigator,
codegen它不会出现在你的导航器,
It's all behind the scenes- you never really see this file
这都是在幕后,你从来没有真正看到这个文件
that is, this codegen file that generates,
这个codegen文件生成,
So don't look for
所以不要找
it there if you put this on class definition,
如果你把这类定义,
This might even be the default actually,
这实际上可能是默认的,
To be Class Definition might be on,
类定义可能在,
But there's other choices in here,
但是有其他的选择,
And the one we choose the most often is Category/Extension,
和我们选择最经常是类别/扩展,
By the way, category just is the Objective-C word for
顺便说一下,类别的objective - c字
extension,
扩展,
Objective-C has something like extensions called categories,
objective - c有类似扩展称为类别,
So that's why it says Category/Extension,
这就是为什么它说类别/扩展,
But you can think in your mind that this just says extension,
但是你可以在你的头脑中认为这只是说扩展,
And what this is gonna do is only generate an extension
这是要做的只是生成一个扩展
of your Tweet class,
你的推类,
You have to actually write the Tweet class itself,
你必须写微博类本身,
But it's all gonna have only your code in it, or
但都是只有你的代码,或
it could be empty if you want,
它可以是空的,如果你想要的,
The extension's gonna take care of all making the vars,
扩展会照顾所有的增值,
Okay, the var magic right there,
好的,var魔法,
So let's see how this works,
让我们看看这是如何工作的,
Even when I switch to Category/Extension,
甚至当我切换到分类/扩展,
Again, I don't get that extension showing up in
我不出现在得到扩展
my navigator,
我的导航器,
It's kind of hidden from you,
这是一种隐藏的你,
Here I'm gonna add the extension way of doing it for
在这里我要添加扩展的方法
TwitterUser too,
TwitterUser也
So both of them, both Tweet and TwitterUser, I'm gonna
所以他们两人,推特和TwitterUser,我要
have an extension generated and, why do we like this one?
生成一个扩展,我们为什么要这样?
Because, a lot of times for
因为,很多时候
our Tweet or TwitterUser we want to add our own code,
我们的推特或TwitterUser我们想添加自己的代码,
Like in a tweet,
像在一条微博,
Imagine you wanted to add a static method that took data
想象你想添加一个静态方法,数据
from Twitter and turned it into a tweet in the database,
来自Twitter和把它变成了一条微博在数据库中,
Where would you put that code?
你把这段代码在哪里?
Well, a great place to put it would be in a tweet class,
一个伟大的地方放它在推类,
if there was such a thing,
如果有这样的事情,
And so, you're in fact, going to create such a thing,
事实上,所以,你要创造这样一个东西,
And the extension is going to handle all of the var business
和var的扩展将处理所有业务
for you,
给你的,
If you did choose Manual/None, right here for Codegen,
如果你选择手动/没有,这里Codegen,
meaning don't do any Codegen, then you're doing value for
意思不做任何Codegen,那么你做的价值
set value for key,
为关键的设置值,
Good luck with that, the code's gonna be a mess, okay?
祝你好运,代码会一团糟,好吗?
So, we almost always do it this way with this extension,
所以,我们几乎总是这样做这个扩展,
Also, if we build our app using multiple modules
同样,如果我们构建应用程序使用多个模块
like we have in Smash Tag, we have a framework module and
就像我们在粉碎标签,我们有一个模块和框架
then we have the main module,
然后我们有主模块,
Then you're probably gonna wanna choose
然后你可能会想选择
from this pull-down here where it says module,
从这个下拉模块,
current product module,
当前的产品模块,
I think if you have a single app that's not modularized
我认为如果你有一个单独的应用程序,不是模块化
like that you probably don't need to set that, but
这样你可能不需要设置,但是
in a multi-modual app you probably do want to,
在你可能想multi-modual应用,
So, since we've chosen here to create only the extension,
所以,既然我们选择这里创建的扩展,
we obviously need to write the code for the classes Tweet And
我们显然需要编写的代码类微博
TwitterUser, we have to create those classes ourselves,
TwitterUser,我们必须创建这些类,
So how do we do that?
那么我们该如何做呢?
Well, just like we create anything,
好吧,就像我们创造任何东西,
we use file, new file,
我们使用文件,新文件,
Then we do file, new file, this time we are back
然后我们做文件,新文件,这一次我们又回来了
to saying it's a cocoa touch class because NSManageObject,
说它是一个因为NSManageObject可可触摸类,
Why is it code called cocoa touch class,
为什么代码叫做可可触摸类,
we wanna make sure we set our super class to be in its
我们要确保我们的超类
managed object, right?
管理对象,对吧?
So, I'm creating a class called Tweet,
所以,我创建一个类称为Tweet,
you see, which is a subclass of NSManagedObject,
你看,这是NSManagedObject的子类,
And is gonna create this for us,
会为我们创建这个,
See? Class Tweet: NSManagedObject,
看到了吗?
No code in there,
没有代码,
That space is for us, we get write anything we want,
空间对我们来说,我们得到写任何我们想要的,
The code that does the vars is in that extension which we
的代码的var在扩展我们
don't even see, but but
甚至没有看到,但是
I'm gonna show it to yo in a second here,
我将展示给你在第二个,
Notice that I picked the name of this class Tweet
注意,我选择这门课的名字
to be the same as the name of the entity in the database,
是一样的实体的名称在数据库中,
which, you want to do,
你想做什么,
It is possible to not do that by inspecting the entity
可以不通过检查实体
in the data model, but, don't do it,
的数据模型,但不这样做,
Just have the entity with the same name,
具有相同名称的实体,
People reading your code are going to expect this class,
阅读代码的人会期待这门课,
this subclass of NSManageObject that
这个子类NSManageObject
represents a tweet,
代表一条微博,
Entity to be called tweet, so called it that,
实体被称为tweet,所以叫它,
Now, we've got an error here, I'll just created this class,
现在,这里有一个错误,我就创建了这个类,
how I'm gonna possibly have an error,
我怎么可能有一个错误,
I'm done anything how could I've done anything wrong?
我做什么怎么做错什么了?
Well, the problem the problem here is,
嗯,这里的问题是问题,
really, Xcode has done something wrong,
真的,Xcode所做的错事,
When Xcode created this, it didn't seem to realize that
当Xcode创建时,它似乎并没有意识到
NSManageObject is not in UIKit,
NSManageObject UIKit,
You see how it put import UIKit at the top?
你看到它如何把进口UIKit顶部吗?
Really, what we need there is import CoreData, okay,
真的,我们需要有进口CoreData,好吧,
All the code that you write,
所有你写的代码,
any time you're doing something in CoreData,
任何时候你做一些CoreData,
you have to import CoreData,
你有进口CoreData,
It's a different framework that the UIKit so
这是一个不同的框架,UIKit
you must import it everywhere that you're going to use it,
你必须导入它无处不在,你要使用它,
Just like we had to import Twitter everywhere we want to
就像无处不在我们想进口Twitter
use that Twitter framework that I gave you,
我给你使用Twitter框架,
So, I don't know why Xcode, I think it's just an oversight
所以,我不知道为什么Xcode,我认为它只是一个监督
Okay?
好吧?
that Xcode when you choose NSManagedObject
,当你选择NSManagedObject Xcode
as your super class you should know, that's in Core Data so
作为超类你应该知道,在核心数据
it should be import Core Data there,
它应该是进口核心数据,
Don't know why it doesn't do that,
不知道为什么它没有这样做,
So here I've created one for the TwitterUser class,
所以我创建了一个用于TwitterUser类,
Again you can put anything you want in there,
你可以把你想要的任何东西,
This is your class,
这是你的类,
You can do anything you want,
你可以做任何你想要的,
All the stuff about the vars is off in
所有的东西在var
an extension somewhere,
一个扩展的地方,
In fact, let's go take a look at that extension,
事实上,我们去看看扩展,
Even though it's not going to show up in your next navigator
即使它不会出现在你的下一个导航器
what it looks like,
它看起来像什么,
you're probably never going to look at it,
你可能永远不会看,
I thought I'd show it to you so
我想展示给你
you understand a little bit what's going on,
你了解一点这是怎么回事,
So, this is the extension, this generated for
这是扩展,这个生成的
TwitterUser,
You see that is an extension
你可以看到这是一个扩展
of the TwitterUser class, right?
TwitterUser类的,对吧?
Remember extensions and it's got the vars,
记得扩展了var,
They're defined not just name and screenName but
他们不仅定义名字和屏幕名
it's got that relationship var tweets as well,
它有这种关系var推,
All right?
好吧?
And look at the type of tweets,
看看微博的类型,
As promised, it's an NSSet, it's an optional because it
作为承诺,NSSet,它是一个可选的,因为它
comes out of the database as not set,
出来的数据库没有设置,
It's gonna get set,
它会得到设置,
So these are the vars,
这些是var,
And I'll talk a little bit about
和我谈一谈
how these vars are actually implemented in a minute but
这些var实际上是如何实现在一分钟吗
all the vars are there,
所有的vars那里,是
There's also some functions,
也有一些功能,
now at the bottom you see those functions,
现在在底部你看到这些功能,
those are kind of fun, those are convenience functions for
这些都是很有趣的,这些都是方便的功能
adding and removing tweets from the tweets set
添加和删除微博的微博
because NSSet is immutable, okay?
因为NSSet是不可变的,对吧?
It's not var verses let like swift things,
这不是var诗句让喜欢斯威夫特的东西,
NS set is kind of old Objective-C way, and NSSet,
NS组是一种古老的objective - c,NSSet,
like NSAttributedString, is immutable, cannot be changed,
像NSAttributedString,是不可变的,无法改变,
so how can I add any tweets to my database here?
那么我可以在这里添加任何推到我的数据库吗?
Well you used these functions instead, add to tweets,
你使用这些函数相反,增加微博,
remove from tweets, add to tweets,
删除微博,添加微博,
remove from tweets, there's a pair for doing a single tweet,
删除从微博,有一对做一个微博,
and there having adding a whole bunch of tweets, or
在加一大堆的tweet,或
removing a whole bunch of tweets, okay?
删除很多微博,好吗?
So you're definitely going to want those functions for
所以你肯定会想要这些功能
your assignment five,
作业五,
Cuz you're gonna have some relationships where you're
因为你会有你的关系
gonna want to add them using these functions,
要想将它们添加使用这些函数,
Now it adds those functions for
现在添加这些功能
any too many relationship, any time you have a too many var
任何太多的关系,任何时候你有太多的var
like tweets, it's going to add these functions automatically
就像微博一样,它会自动添加这些功能
It actually put it in its own little extension, this file
它实际上把它放在自己的扩展,这个文件
in the extensions,
在扩展,
has two extensions in it, both through TwitterUser,
有两个扩展,通过TwitterUser,
Any questions about extensions there or any of that?
任何扩展或有任何问题吗?
Okay, let's look at tweets extension real quick,
好吧,让我们来看看微博扩展很快,
Couple other things to look at here that I didn't look
看一些其他的内容我没有看
in the other one,
在另一个,
Notice this static func called fetchRequest?
注意到这个静态函数称为fetchRequest吗?
Put that in your mind,
把它放在你的思想,
I'm gonna talk about that in a few slides,
我要讲几张幻灯片,
fetchRequest is a really cool little static func that will
fetchRequest是一个很酷的小静态函数
give you something you can use to fetch tweets,
给你一些你可以用来获取tweet,
And if you call fetchrRquest on twitter users,
如果你打电话给fetchrRquest twitter用户,
you'll get something to fetch twitter users,
你会获取twitter用户,
And we'll talk about all about fetch in a moment here,
我们会讨论关于引进一个时刻,
Notice the type of tweeter, see the tweeter var,
注意到推特的类型,看到推特var,
Its type is TwitterUser,
它的类型是TwitterUser,
Because of course that's what the tweeter is,
因为这是推特,
we control drag between the tweet and the tweeter user so
我们控制拖在微博和推特用户
that tweeter var is of course a tweeter user,
推特var当然是推特的用户,
not an NSSet, because it's a two one relationship, okay,
不是NSSet,因为它是一二一的关系,好吧,
there's only one TwitterUser, who is my tweeter,
只有一个TwitterUser,谁是我的推特,
And what about this @NSManaged?
这@NSManaged呢?
Okay, @NSManaged I'm just gonna say it's magic,
好的,@NSManaged我会说这是魔法,
It's not really magic,
这不是魔术,
It's essentially something that says to the runtime, hey,
它本质上是说到运行时的东西,嘿,
When someone accesses this var,
当有人访问这个变量,
Core Data's gonna figure it out for you,
核心数据会算出来给你,
And what Core Data does, is when you try to say
什么核心数据,当你试图说
Tweet,created equals some date, it gets trapped
推特,创建等于某个日期,它被困
at a low level in the runtime and Core Data swoops in and
在一个较低水平,俯冲而下,在运行时和核心数据
does set value for key for you, okay,
设置值为关键,好的,
Same thing if you get the created var, it swoops in and
同样的事情如果你创建的var,俯冲而下
does value for key and gets it that way,
对关键值,这样,
But it's all happening at a low level behind the scenes,
但这都是发生在一个较低水平,在幕后,
So this extension does satisfy the extension limitation where
这扩展并满足扩展限制
it can't have any storage,
它不能有任何存储,
All of the storage for these vars isn't in the database,
所有的数据库中存储这些var不是,
And when you ask for it,
当你问,
Or when you set it, it's using its value for
或者当你设置它,使用它的价值
key instead of value for key, to set it in the database,
关键值的键,设置它在数据库中,
Now again, it sets in memory,
现在,它集在内存中,
You have to save it for
你必须保存它
it to actually go out into the database,
实际上,出去到数据库中,
But that what's happening,
但是,发生了什么,
All right, so
好吧,那么
now that we have these class so here's some
现在,这里是一些我们有这些类
code that creates a tweets and sets it's attributes, okay so
代码创建一个tweet,并设置它的属性,所以
let's look at this piece by piece and see what it does,
让我们看看这一块一块的,看看,
The first thing is to create a tweet, we don't have to do
第一件事是创建一个tweet,我们不需要做
NSEntityDescription, Entity, insert Entity for name into
NSEntityDescription,实体,实体名称插入
contacts, or whatever that huge, long terrible thing was-
联系人,或任何巨大,长——可怕的事情
we can just say, tweet, parenthesis context,
我们可以说,推特,括号的背景下,
You just say what context, which means what database you
你说什么情况下,这意味着你的数据库
want the tweet to put in and it creates a new tweet,
希望推放在它创建一个新的微博,
Okay, just use a normal initializer for
好的,只使用一个正常初始化
new things so that's super cool,
新事物,这样的超级酷,
That's one of the coolest features right there,
这是最酷的功能之一,
Not having to use an NSEntityDescription thing, so
没有使用一个NSEntityDescription事情,所以
no more NSEntityDescription, we'll not have to do that,
NSEntityDescription,我们不需要这样做,
And then here,
然后在这里,
I'm setting the text to be 140 characters of pure joy,
我要140个字符设置文本纯粹的快乐,
And I don't have to say set value 140 characters of pure
我不必说值140个字符的纯
joy for key text and have all these literal strings like
快乐关键文本和所有这些字符串
text in there in this untyped thing,
文本在这无类型的事情,
I just say tweet,text equals that,
我只是说推特,文本=,
And the same thing here with created, again, so we don't
和创建同样的事,所以我们不
even have to worry about the thing, if we tried to say
甚至需要担心的事情,如果我们试图说
tweet,created equals quote hello, this Swift would say,
推特,创造=报价你好,我迅速会说,
no, created is of type Date, so you can't do that, so
不,创建日期类型,所以你不能这样做
it finds all of our, it type checks everything,
它发现我们所有的类型检查一切,
finds all of our possible errors,
发现我们所有的可能的错误,
What about relationships, okay, setting relationships?
是什么关系,设置关系?
So here I've created another object, a TwitterUser and
所以我创建了另一个对象,TwitterUser和
again I just set TwitterUser with a context,
我刚和一个上下文设置TwitterUser,
I'll talk about that argument in just a second but
我将讨论这个论点只是一秒
I told what database I wanna create in TwitterUser and
我告诉什么我想创建TwitterUser和数据库
I set my tweet's tweeter equal to that TwitterUser,
我把我的推特的推特TwitterUser等于,
So, it's exactly what you're, would imagine right?
所以,这就是你,想象对吗?
Just set it equal to Joe,
把它等于乔,
And what's interesting about this is that when you set one
有趣的是,当你设置一个
side of a relationship, the other side gets updated
方的关系,另一方得到更新
automatically, 100% of the time,
自动,100%的时间,
This is call maintaining
这是呼叫保持
the integrity of the database, okay?
数据库的完整性,对吧?
And Core Data always maintains database integrity,
和核心数据总是保持数据库的完整性,
So, when you change one side relationship,
所以,当你改变一方的关系,
It changes the other,
它改变了,
So, that means for example if I say tweet,tweeter
所以,这意味着例如如果我说推特,推特
equals Joe, then if I went over to the Joe side and
等于乔,那么如果我走到乔一边
said hey give me Joe's tweets and I'm even gonna turn it
说嗨乔给我的推特,我甚至会把它
into a Swift kind of set from an NSSet to a set of
为一种快速组从NSSet到一组
tweet because we know that's what tweets are, right?
微博因为我们知道微博是什么,对吧?
Tweets are a set of Tweets, so I'm gonna as it to do that,
推特是一组微博,所以我要这样做,
Then I can say, if Joe's tweet contains that tweet print yes
我可以说,如果乔的这条微博包含打印是的
and of course it is going to print yes,
当然,它将打印是的,
Because when I said tweet,tweeter = joe,
因为当我说推特,推特=乔,
it automatically got added to joe's tweets,
它会自动添加到乔的微博,
That make sense?
这说得通吗?
And same thing the other way,
一样和其他方式,
If I added a tweet into joe's tweets,
如果我添加了一个推到乔的微博,
that tweet tweeter would automatically set to be joe,
微博推特会自动将乔,
Okay? Both sides will always
好吧?
point to each other,
指向对方,
You never have to do anything to make that happen,
你不必做任何事情发生,
tweet,tweeter=joe is exactly
推特,推特=乔就是
the same as saying joe dot addToTweets tweet,
说乔•addToTweets tweet,一样
Remember addToTweets is one of those convenience functions
记住addToTweets是其中的一个便利的函数
that it created for us over there,
它为我们创造了,
Now, notice the argument I used for
现在,请注意我用的论证
the context to create the Twitter user there,
上下文创建Twitter用户,
I didn't say AppDelegate,viewContext,
我没有说AppDelegate viewContext,
I didn't use that same context bar that I had,
我没有使用相同的上下文酒吧,我,
I said tweet,manageObjectContext,
我说推特,manageObjectContext,
In other words, I got, I found out what database the tweet is
换句话说,我得到了,我发现数据库的微博是什么
in, and I put the Twitter user in the same database,
,我把Twitter用户在同一个数据库中,
And this is a common way of programming in Core Data
这是一个编程的核心数据的常用方法
where when you wanna get a context and
当你想要一个上下文,在哪里
you already have a object in the database you
你已经有一个数据库中的对象
ask the object you already have what context to use,
问你的对象已经有什么情况下使用,
And you can see that if I ever change my code to not put this
你可以看到,如果我不把这个曾经改变我的代码
into this context, to put it into another context, at least
在这种情况下,至少把它放到另一个上下文
the Twitter user and the tweet would always be together
Twitter用户和微博将永远在一起
in whatever that context is,
不管上下文,
So you can see why I used the tweets can't
所以你可以看到我为什么微博不能使用
manage object context here to create that instead of using
管理对象上下文创建,而不是使用
the context again,
再次,
So, it, it would work to say context, of course,
所以,说工作背景下,当然,
but I'm just saying there's a paradigm of development where
但我只是说有一个范式的发展
we're gonna try and use the context of related object,
我们将尝试使用上下文相关的对象,
So they end up in the same database for sure,
所以他们最终在同一个数据库中,
Okay?
好吧?
All right, so
好吧,那么
we can also use dot notation, because these are just vars,
我们还可以使用点符号,因为这些只是var,
So when I say tweet,tweeter, I get a TwitterUser object,
所以当我说推特,推特,我得到一个TwitterUser对象,
So, of course, I can say dot name on it and
当然,我能说点的名字
set it equal to Joe Schmo, whatever, right?
令它等于乔愚人等等,对吗?
tweet,tweeter,name = "Joe Schmo", all right?
推特,推特,name = "乔愚人”,对吧?
No restriction there on those vars,
没有限制的var,
All right, remember I told you about the scalars?
好吧,记住我告诉你的标量吗?
This is that switch I was telling you about before,
这是开关我之前告诉你,
If you don't do this, then when you say,
如果你不这样做,当你说,
if you had an int, let's say you had retweet
如果你有一个int,假设你已经转发
count which was an int here let's say on Int32,
数是一个int假设Int32,
If you don't switch this button,
如果你没有这个按钮,切换
then that's going to be an NSNumber not an Int32,
那是一个NSNumber不是Int32,
But when you click this switch on,
但是当你点击这个开关,
now that var will be of type Int32,
现在,var将Int32类型,
So you almost always want this for numbers,
所以你几乎总是希望这个数字,
99,9% of the time, you want to have this switch on,
99年,9%的时间,你想有一个开关,
Luckily, it's on by default so
幸运的是,它在默认情况下
you don't even have to think about it much, but
你甚至不需要过多地考虑这些,但是
I just wanted to let you know about it,
我只是想让你知道,
All right, so now lets talk about deletion,
好,现在让我们谈谈删除,
Okay, now, I want to delete something from the database,
好的,现在,我想从数据库删除一个条目,
And that's incredibly easy,
这是令人难以置信的简单,
almost too easy because your data's precious you don't want
几乎太简单了,因为你的数据是宝贵的你不想要
to be deleting it to easily, but you do that by asking
删除它很容易,但你问
the context to delete the NSManagedObject, so you can
中删除的NSManagedObject,这样你就可以
pass any NSManagedObject to this method delete and
通过任何NSManagedObject这种方法删除
it will delete it from the database,
它将从数据库中删除它,
And it could cascade and delete other things as well
和它可以级联删除其他的事情
depending on what delete rule is, all right?
根据删除规则是什么,对吧?
Most of the time by default, when I delete something,
大部分时间在默认情况下,当我删除一些东西,
other things that point to it get that pointer set to nil,
其他的东西,它的指针指向的设置为零,
That's the nullify delete rule,
这是取消删除规则,
Now, when things get deleted from the database they got
现在,当事情变得从数据库中删除
sent this message first, prepare for deletion,
先发送此消息,准备删除,
Okay, and this is a really good method,
好吧,这是一个很好的方法,
Again, in here you don't have to do anything
同样,在这里你不需要做任何事
to worry about the other pointers point to you
担心另一个指针指向你
that's all fixed by the delete rule,
删除所有固定的规则,
But what if you had another field in your database?
但是如果你有另一个字段在数据库中?
Back to the retweet count example again,
再次转发数的例子,
Let's say I had an int somewhere in TwitterUser,
假设有一个int在TwitterUser某处,
which counted the number of retweets
计算转发的数量
that this twitter user had done,
这个twitter用户所做的,
And so if I was deleting a tweet and it happened to be
如果我删除微博,它的发生而笑
a retweet then I need to set that to be minus equal one,
转发,那么我需要设置- = 1,
And here's the perfect place to do it,
这是完美的地方,
So tweet, and it's prepared for
所以微博,准备
deletion saying whoop, I'm about to be deleted,
删除说一点点,我要被删除,
I'd better tell my Twitter user, cuz I'm a retweet,
我最好告诉我的Twitter用户,因为我是一个转发,
that he needs to decrement his retweet count,
他需要减量转发数,
So you see why you would use prepare for deletion?
所以你知道为什么你会使用准备删除?
It's a way to kind of update other things in the database
它是一种方法的更新数据库中的其他事情
when as you're leaving the database,
当你要离开数据库,
All right, so that's it for deletion,
好了,这就是删除,
Next topic, querying,
下一个话题、查询
the most important piece of this whole database thing,
整个数据库最重要的东西,
It's really a waste of time doing all this stuff if you're
这真是浪费时间做这些东西如果你
not gonna query, okay?
不会查询,好吗?
If you're not gonna make sophisticated requests for
如果你不会做复杂的要求
the information based on the relationships, etc,
基于关系的信息,等等,
So, to do a query the most important thing you need to
所以,做一个查询你所需要的最重要的事
know is NSFetchRequest, this class NSFetchRequest,
知道这类NSFetchRequest NSFetchRequest,,
And NSFetchRequest encapsulates
和NSFetchRequest封装
what you want from the database,
你想要从数据库中,
So let's talk about an NSFetchRequest and
所以让我们来谈谈一个NSFetchRequest和
how we build one,
如何构建一个,
So when we're building one,
所以当我们正在构建一个,
there's three important things we need to know,
有三个重要的事情我们需要知道,
One, what entity are we fetching?
1、我们抓取的实体是什么?
Because a FetchRequest can only Fetch one kind of entity,
因为FetchRequest只能获取一种实体,
You can, there's no such thing a FetchRequest that will give
可以,没有这样的事FetchRequest给
you some tweet and some Twitter user,
你一些推特和Twitter用户,
No, okay?
不,好吗?
A fetch always gives you all tweets or
获取总是给你所有微博或
all Twitter users, make sense?
Twitter的用户,有意义吗?
So that's the number one thing,
这是一件事,
is we're gonna create the fetch request,
我们要创建获取请求,
And it will be a fetch request or a very specific entity,
这将是一个获取请求或一个非常具体的实体,
And it will only be able to fetch those entities,
它只能取回这些实体,
The second thing is is an array of sort descriptors,
第二件事是数组类型描述符,
And why do we want this?
为什么我们想要的吗?
Because when we execute this fetch it's gonna come back
因为当我们执行这个取回它会回来
as an array, okay?
作为一个数组,好吗?
All the matching tweets or
所有匹配的tweet
Twitter user will come back in an array,
Twitter用户会回来在一个数组,
And since it's an array,
因为它是一个数组,
arrays are not sets, arrays are ordered and so
数组不是集,数组是有序的,所以
we have specify what order the things are in the arrays,
我们已经指定数组中的事情,
So we do that with these sort descriptors,
所以我们使用这类描述符,
And finally, we just specify or what is it that we want,
最后,我们只是指定或者我们想要什么,
which tweets do we want, which Twitter users do we want and
微博我们想要,Twitter用户做我们想要的吗
we do that with something called a predicate,
我们所做的,在一个叫做谓词,
Okay, so let's dive in and
好的,让我们在和潜水
look at all three of these things,
看看这三个东西,
This is what it looks like,
这就是它的样子,
kinda top level to create a fetch request,
有点顶层创建获取请求,
Okay, you get a fetch request,
好的,你会得到一个获取请求,
You set the source descriptor and you set its predicate,
你设置源描述符设置它的谓语,
So you get each of these three parts,
所以这三个部分,
So getting the fetch request is easy,
所以获取请求是很容易的,
We're gonna use that little static function
我们将使用这个小静态函数
that the extension that I talked about, made for
我谈到的扩展,使
us called fetchRequest,
我们叫fetchRequest,
Now, this is one of the very few times when Swift
现在,这是为数不多的时候迅速
cannot infer the type of this return value,
不能推断出这个返回值的类型,
Should've put this in red, okay?
应该把这个红色的,好吗?
Because it's so
因为它是如此
rare, Swift can almost always infer things,
罕见,斯威夫特几乎总是可以推断,
But in turns out NSManagedObject
但在NSManagedObject
has a fetchRequest method and it returns the more generic
有一个fetchRequest方法,它返回更通用的
kind of fetchRequest and so when you're getting it,
种fetchRequest所以当你得到它,
it doesn't quite know which one you want,
完全不知道你想要哪一个,
So when you ask a Tweet for
所以,当你问一个Tweet
its fetch request right here, you have to tell it did you
其获取请求,你必须告诉你
want the one in Tweet not the one from its super class?
想要一个在推特不是一个从其超类?
All right? And so
好吧?
say let request equal NSFetchRequest,
说让请求NSFetchRequest相等,
It's a generic type like array or something like that, right?
这是一个泛型类型数组或类似的东西,对吧?
This is a fetch request only for Tweets,
这是一个只有微博获取请求,
So you say NSFetchRequest =
所以你说NSFetchRequest  =
Tweet,fetchRequest(),
微博,fetchRequest(),
And it knows, of course,
当然,它知道
that the only one that returns an NSFetchRequest for
返回一个NSFetchRequest的只有一个
tweets is the fetchRequest, and that's Tweet extension,
微博是fetchRequest,微博扩展,
So now, you have a fetchRequest,
现在,你有一个fetchRequest,
this is how you get a fetch request- couldn't be easier,
这是你如何获取请求,不容易,
You just have to remember to do that static
你只需要记住这样做静态的
typing right there,
打字,
Okay, now we need the sortDescriptor, right?
好了,现在我们需要sortDescriptor ?
It's got this array coming back,
它有这个数组返回,
What order are they going to be?
他们会是什么订单?
SortDescriptor looks like this,
SortDescriptor看起来是这样的,
You create it with a key,
您创建一个关键,
That is the key, the attribute in
这就是关键,属性
the database that you want to sort on, so the screen name or
上你想要的数据库,所以屏幕名称或
even the text in the tweet or the actual name of
甚至微博中的文本或实际的名称
the tweeter, whatever it's gonna be,
推特,不管它是什么,
This right here, sortDescriptor,
这里,sortDescriptor,
will be a sort descriptor only suitable for fetching Twitter
将一个类描述符只适用于抓取微博
users, because screenName is a key in Twitter user,
用户,因为在Twitter用户屏幕名是一个关键,
not in tweet, so we're gonna use this SortDescriptor
没有推特,所以我们要使用这个SortDescriptor
in a tweet request,
要求,在推特上
And I say that because on the previous slide,
我说,因为之前的幻灯片上,
I just showed you how to make a fetch request for a tweet,
我只是向您展示了如何获取请求一条微博,
Anyway, I should just, that should have been Twitter user,
无论如何,我应该,应该是Twitter用户,
But anyway, so this is a Twitter user,
但无论如何,这是一个Twitter用户,
SortDescriptor,
And notice it has ascending or descending like us A to Z or
注意它有像我们这样的升序或降序A到Z
Z to A and then it has this argument selector and
Z,然后它有这个参数选择器
this one creates some confusion,
这个造成了一些困惑,
But really this selector just says,
但实际上这选择器只是说,
what method am I gonna use to compare items to do the sort,
我要用什么方法来比较项目排序,
All right now, you don't even have to specify the selector
现在好了,你甚至不需要指定选择器
if you don't want to and for
如果你不想
almost all data types, numbers,
几乎所有的数据类型、数字
dates, it's going to use a method called compare, okay,
日期,它会使用一种称为比较,好吧,
Compare returns something called a comparison result
返回一个叫做比较结果进行比较
which is either, it's the same, it's greater than, or
不是,是一样的,大于,还是
it's less than,
不到,
So, that's what this compare method does,
所以,这就是这个方法并进行比较,
And it's implemented by date,
实施日期,
It's implemented by Int32,
这是由Int32,实现
It's implemented by double,
它是实现双,
It's even implemented by string,
甚至实现字符串,
Okay? So,
好吧?
you could just use compare,
你可以使用比较,
But, for strings,
但是,对于字符串,
You wanna think a little bit about what kind
你想要一点思考什么
of comparison do you want?
你想要比较的?
Do you want case-insensitive compare?
你想要以不区分大小写的比较吗?
Or you could even use this special compare,
或者你甚至可以使用这种特殊的比较,
called localizedStandardCompare,
叫localizedStandardCompare,
This will compare them so
这将比较他们
that it is sourced just like the finder on the Mac,
这是采购就像仪在Mac上,
And what does the finder on the Mac do that's different
的发现者在Mac上做的不同的事情
than case insensitive?
比不区分大小写吗?
Well, there's a lot of issues with things like diacritic
嗯,有很多诸如可区别的问题
marks, and you know,
是,你知道,
things in your local language where things sort differently,
事情在你的当地语言不同,
depending on what language you're in, what locale it is,
取决于你在什么语言,语言环境是什么,
You'd, you sometimes you ignore the diacritics,
你,你有时候你忽略变音符号,
like accent marks,
像重音符号,
Sometimes they mean something,
有时他们的意思是什么,
And, so localized standard compare is a special compare
因此本地化标准的比较是一种特殊的比较
for strings, that knows how to do that, okay?
字符串,知道怎么做,好吗?
And this is very commonly the one we will use for strings,
这是非常常见的一个我们将使用字符串,
When we're gonna show something in our UI,
当我们将展示一些在我们的界面,
maybe this array of thing for fetching,
也许这一系列的抓取,
we're gonna put it in the UI,
我们要把它在UI中,
We would want it to be in order,
我们会想要,
this localizedStandardCompare,
这个localizedStandardCompare,
You notice that it's an NSString dot method,
你注意到这是一个NSString点方法,
It's not String,localizedStandardComp-
这不是字符串,localizedStandardComp -
that's because this has to be an Objective-C visible method,
因为这是一个objective - c可见的方法,
are, And
是,
And you need the NSString version,
你需要NSString版本,
So basically you're going to say NSString dot, and
所以基本上你要说NSString点,和
you can go look, search for compare in NSString or string,
你可以去看,寻找比较NSString或字符串,
because a string implements them all as well but
但是因为一个字符串来实现
you need NSString dot and then the name of the method,
你需要NSString点方法的名称,
And you can search, and there is case insensitive and
你可以搜索,不分大小写
the standard compare and then the regular compare and etc,
标准的比较,然后定期比较等,
Now one other thing about this is that,
现在另一件事是,
these methods some of them are special in that,
这些方法有些特殊,
it does to compare on the database side, okay,
它确实比较在数据库方面,好的,
Using SQL to do it, see what I'm saying?
使用SQL,看到我在说什么吗?
It's not actually bringing all the data over,
实际上并不是把所有的数据,
Calling this method on every string, and
在每一个字符串,调用该方法
doing some kind of quicksort or something,
做一些快速排序,
It's using super powerful sorting mechanisms that
这是使用超级强大的排序机制
are built into an SQL database, okay,
构建成一个SQL数据库,
So, in fact, all of the NSString ones will do that,
事实上,所有NSString的都会这样做,
Okay, so they're super duper efficient,
好的,所以他们超级有效,
Now, if you wanted to use your own compare though,
现在,如果你想使用自己的比较,
it's not gonna be efficient,
它不会有效,
Because it is gonna have to
因为这是必须的
bring all the data from the database into your memory so
把所有的数据从数据库到你的记忆
it can run your little method over it,
它可以运行你的小方法,
So I strongly recommend
所以我强烈推荐
against using your own selector here,
不要使用你自己的选择,
I would use the standard selectors,
我将使用标准的选择器,
If you're gonna use your own selector
如果你要使用自己的选择器
it's gotta be on a pretty small dataset,
它应该是在一个非常小的数据集,
Cuz it's not gonna be very efficient,
因为它不会很有效,
Notice that when we do the fetch request,
注意,当我们获取请求,
we don't just give it a sort descriptor,
我们不只是给它一个描述符,
we give it an array of sort descriptors,
我们给它一个数组的类型描述符,
That's the old sort by last name, and then first name,
这是老按姓排序,然后名字,
Right? So if
对吧?
we have 12 Smiths in there, we'll sort them and
我们有12个铁匠,排序
the Smiths will be in the right spot,
史密斯一家将在正确的位置,
And then all of the first names of the Smiths
然后所有的史密斯的名字
will be in order by that,
将在订单,
So we can have as many of these sub sort by the one
所以我们可以有许多的这些子
thing, sub sort by the next thing,
子类型,接下来,
sub sort by the next thing,
子,接下来,
Basically, we can break ties with subsequent sorting and
基本上,我们可以打破与随后的排序和的关系
that's why we give an array of sort descriptors,
这就是为什么我们给一个数组类型描述符,
Okay, so, that's the fetch request and
好了,这就是获取请求和
its sort descriptors and now the predicate,
类型描述符和谓词,
Okay, the predicate is the guts of saying which tweets do
谓词是勇气说的tweet
we want,
我们想要的,
Which Twitter users do we want?
我们想要的Twitter用户?
We create them with kind of interesting API,
我们用有趣的API创建它们,
It looks a lot like printf from C,
它看起来很像printf从C,
NSPredicate format colon, and then a string,
结肠NSPredicate格式,然后一个字符串,
And the string is a format string,
是一个格式字符串和字符串,
And again, looks a lot like printf,
看起来很像printf,
So the best way to explain this is probably by example,
所以最好的方法解释这可能是以身作则,
But the way you're gonna learn this is you're gonna go
但是你要学习这个的方式是你要走了
read the documentation for NSPredicate, you've got to go
NSPredicate阅读文档,你必须去
read that documentation, in its class documentation,
阅读文档,在它的类文档,
there's gonna be a link that says, creating predicates,
会有一个链接,创建谓词,
or something like that, click on that, and go there, and
之类的,点击,和去那里
learn all the things you can put in this format string,
学习所有的东西你可以把这种格式字符串,
cuz it's all very specific to doing database queries, but
因为这都是非常特定于数据库查询,但是
I'll show you some examples, so
我将向您展示一些例子
you get an idea of what's going on here,
你知道这是怎么回事,
So here's the first one,
这是第一个,
let's have the search string called foo,
让我们搜索字符串foo,
All these searches then I'm gonna do right here
然后我要做所有这些搜索在这里
are tweet searches,
微博搜索,
These are for predicates for searching for a tweet,
这些都是为寻找一条微博,谓词
So first, I'm gonna find all the tweets whose text,
首先,我要找到所有的消息文本,
the actual tweet, the 140 characters of pure joy or
实际的推特,140个字符或纯粹的快乐
whatever, contains case sensitive,
无论如何,包含大小写敏感的,
Case insensitively,
区分大小写,
That's what [c] means,
这就是[c]的意思,
%@, %@ is a substitution variable,
% @ % @,是替代变量,
and I have to give its value at the end,
最后,我不得不给它的价值,
And so I'm substituting search string,
所以我用搜索字符串,
Okay, note that I can't say, text contains foo,
好的,请注意,我不能说,文本包含foo,
I have to say, text contains %@ and then,
我不得不说,文本包含% @然后,
Put something at the end there,
最后放点东西,
Okay, so that's an obvious one,
好了,这是很明显的一个,
I'm searching for all my tweets that contain foo,
我寻找我的所有包含foo的微博,
How about this one?
这一个怎么样?
I want all the tweets whose tweeter equals %@,
我希望所有的推特的推特= % @,
I'm going to put Joe in there as the substitution variable
我要把乔作为替代变量
and created after some date that I create,
后,创建一些我创建的日期,
See that? I'm using greater
看到了吗?
than to do that,
比,
And I'm doing && for and,
和我做& &,
you can also use the word and there,
你也可以用这个词,
Okay? So that's all gonna be
好吧?
the tweets created by Joe since that date,
自那天起,乔创造的微博,
You're starting to see the power of building the query
你开始看到的力量构建查询
into the database, right?
到数据库中,对吧?
If I had thousands of tweets, it'd be really easy to find
如果我有成千上万的微博,会很容易找到的
the ones since yesterday, for example,
例如,从昨天开始的
I'll show you that in a second here,
我将向您展示,在这里,
Aand then I can also though, search through dot notation,
不过,和然后我也可以搜索点符号,
on other fields, in other entities, but
在其他领域,在其他实体,但是
this tweeter,screenName equals percent @ sign%@ with CS193P,
这个推特,与CS193P屏幕名= % @ % @,
that's still searching for tweets,
这仍然是搜索微博,
That's searching for
这是寻找
tweets whose tweeter's screen name is CS193P,
推的推特的屏幕名字是CS193P,
Do you see what it's doing there?
你看到它在做什么?
This is still a tweet predicate,
这仍然是一个tweet谓词,
This is not a twitter user predicate,
这不是一个twitter用户谓词,
Okay?
好吧?
So here's a different predicate,
这是一个不同的谓语,
This one is for Twitter user,
这是Twitter用户,
So here I'm searching for all the Twitter users
这里我寻找所有的Twitter用户
Okay?
好吧?
who has a Tweet whose text contains foo,
谁有一个微博,其文本包含foo,
Okay?
好吧?
So it even knows how to do a pluralistic
所以即使知道如何做一个多元化
search right here where you've got tweets dot text that means
搜索在这里,这意味着你有微博点文本
all the tweets, texts and doing contains and
所有的微博,包含文本和做
we can do [c] if we wanted foo,
我们可以做[c]如果我们希望foo,
So that's a twitter user search right there,
这是一个twitter用户搜索,
the twitter users who have tweeted anything that includes
twitter用户,包括任何东西
We're looking for
我们正在寻找
foo, again a powerful search, really easy to express,
foo,再强大的搜索,很容易表达,
Question,
问题,
>> [INAUDIBLE] >> So the question,
> > > >(听不清)问题,
does it infer this from the name of the variable,
它推断出这个名字的变量,
it's not inferring it,
这不是推断,
it's actually using the name of the attribute tweets
它实际上是使用的名称属性的微博
right there and the name of the attribute text and it's
这里和文本的属性的名称
building a SQL statement that will go and do this fetch,
建立一个SQL语句,会去做这个取回,
Okay now it's doing all that underneath the covers,
好了现在这么做封面,下面
we don't care how, but it's doing it,
我们不关心,但这样做,
Yeah, compound predicate,
是的,复合谓语,
You can build a compound predicate like an and
您可以构建一个复合谓词和
predicate or an or predicate,
谓词或一个谓词,
You could put or or and in the string, or
你可以把或字符串,或
you could create separate predicates and and
你可以创建单独的谓词和
them together by creating an NSCompoundPredicate,
通过创建一个NSCompoundPredicate一起,
And predicate with sub-predicates, and
与sub-predicates和谓词,
just given an array of predicates and
给出一个谓词和数组
it ands them together,
它and一起,
Why would you ever want to do this versus just putting and
为什么你会想要这样做只有把和吗
or, or in there?
或者,还是在那里?
Well, maybe you're computing what the predicates are,
好吧,也许你计算谓词是什么,
based on some, depending on what the user clicked on or
基于一些,这取决于用户点击或
something, you're computing it, and
什么,你计算它,
so you want to add these things you computed together,
所以你想要添加这些东西一起计算,
All right, there's also function predicates,
好吧,还有谓词函数,
Now these are super powerful predicates,
现在这些都是超级强大的谓词,
and you don't need these for your homework, so
并为你的作业,你不需要这些
don't worry too much about these, but they're cool,
不要过于担心这些,但是他们很酷,
You can even say, you have a search like this one,
你甚至会说,你有一个像这样的搜索,
tweets,@count > 5,
微博,@count > 5,
this is a Twitter user search, that finds
这是一个Twitter用户搜索,发现
all the Twitter users who have more than 5 Tweets, okay?
所有的Twitter用户已超过5条,好吗?
So, @count is actually running, kind of a function in
所以,@count实际运行,一种功能
the database, to go count the number of Tweets that
数据库,去数一数的tweet
the Twitter user has,
Twitter用户,
So, again, you'll see all of this when you go look at
再说一遍,你会发现当你去看
the NSPredicate documentation, it's incredibly powerful,
NSPredicate文档,这是令人难以置信的强大,
you can see you barely have to type anything in as the format
你可以看到你几乎没有输入任何格式
string, and you get these really powerful searches,
字符串,得到这些真正强大的搜索,
All right, so let's put it all together now to create
好了,现在让我们把它放在一起来创建
our fetch request, okay,
我们获取请求,
I'm gonna create,
我要创建、
in this case, a Twitter user fetch request,
在这种情况下,一个Twitter用户获取请求,
So I'm saying a FetchRequest =
所以我说一个FetchRequest  =
TwitterUser,fetchRequest(), then I'm gonna
TwitterUser,fetchRequest(),然后我要
create a time which was yesterday,
创建一个时间是昨天,
it's actually not, it's 24 hours ago,
其实不是,这是24小时前,
Time interval since now, minus 24 times 60 times 60,
时间间隔从现在,- 24 * 60 * 60,
that's 24 hours ago, and I'm creating a predicate
24小时前,我正在创建一个谓词
that says, find me any Twitter users that have a Tweet that's
说,发现我任何Twitter用户的Tweet
created before yesterday, or since yesterday I guess,
昨天之前创建的,或从昨天我猜,
yes, created is greater than yesterday,
是的,昨天创造大于,
So I'm finding all the Twitter users who have created Tweets
我发现所有的Twitter用户创建的tweet
in the last twenty-four hours, that's what this one does,
在过去的24小时,这就是这一个,
So any is a special term that means match any
所以是一个特殊的词,它意味着匹配任何
of these things, and
这些东西,
these things are Tweets that are created since yesterday,
这些都是创建从昨天的微博,
And I'm gonna sort the result by the actual name,
我将排序结果的实际名称,
the real name of the Twitter user,
Twitter用户的真实姓名,
So I'm just doing sortDescriptor, key of name,
我只是做sortDescriptor,关键的名字,
ascending true, I'm not specifying a selector, so
提升真的,我不是指定一个选择器
I'm gonna get kind of the default comparison,
我要得到默认的比较,
Okay, that's it, so that's how you create a fetch request,
好吧,就这样,这就是你创建一个获取请求,
Now, since I have a fetch request, how do I make it go?
现在,因为我有一个获取请求,我怎么去吗?
Give me those Tweets, give me those Twitter users,
给我那些微博,给我这些Twitter用户,
We do that with the very simple method in context, so
我们做的非常简单的方法在上下文,所以
we ask the context to do the fetch, and it will go out and
我们问下取回,并将出去
return an array of all those things,
返回一个数组的所有这些事情,
sorted in the way the fetch request says to sort them,
排序的方式获取请求说他们,
Okay, simple as that,
好吧,就这么简单,
The only thing not so simple, it throws, okay?
唯一没有这么简单,它把,好吗?
Just like context save throws, context execute also throws,
就像上下文保存抛出,上下文执行也抛出,
So, you could put in a try question mark,
所以,你可以试着问号,
in that case, if the execute fails, and usually it's gonna
在这种情况下,如果执行失败,通常它会
fail because your predicate is wrong, or something,
失败,因为你的谓词是错误的,或者别的什么,
Like your predicate just makes no sense then you could fail,
喜欢你的谓语就毫无意义,那么你可以失败,
If it's gonna fail, you're gonna get back nil,
如果它会失败,你会回到零,
if you do try question mark,
如果你试着问号,
remember that's what try question mark means,
记住,就是试着问号的意思,
It means try this, and if it fails, give back nil,
这意味着试试这个,如果失败,返回nil,
But it if doesn't fail,
但如果不失败,
then you're gonna get an optional array,
然后你会得到一个可选的数组,
And that array is gonna be empty,
数组是空,
if it couldn't find anything that matches your request, or,
如果找不到任何匹配你的要求,或者,
it's gonna be full of objects, okay?
它会布满对象,好吗?
Tweets, or Twitter users, an array of tweets, or
微博,或Twitter用户,一个tweet数组,或
an array of Twitter users,
一个Twitter用户数组,
at least that's what it's gonna look like to you,
至少它会是什么样子,
it's not quite that, looks like it, all right?
看起来,它不是很好吗?
That's the result you're gonna get back, so, again,
结果你会回来,所以,再一次,
super simple querying,
超级简单的查询,
Now, you might be a little scared of doing this request,
现在,你可能有点害怕做这个请求,
what if it's matches a million things, okay?
如果匹配一百万件事,好吗?
Are you gonna get a million Tweets back in one
你要拿回一百万条在一个
request like this?
这样的请求吗?
The answer is no,
答案是否定的,
This array that you get back is really super smart array,
这个数组,你回来是非常聪明的数组,
It doesn't actually bring the data in from the database,
它实际上并不带来从数据库中的数据,
until you start asking for it, okay?
直到你开始问,好吗?
So until I ask for the Twitter user,
所以,直到我问Twitter用户,
a certain Twitter user's information,
一个Twitter用户的信息,
the Twitter user's name, the Twitter user's screen name,
Twitter用户的名称、Twitter用户的屏幕名字,
the Twitter user did not get faulted from the database,
Twitter用户从数据库中没有得到断裂,
This is called faulting, okay?
这就是所谓的断层,好吗?
And so, these objects, you can imagine,
因此,这些对象,你可以想象,
they're kind of shells, empty shells,
它们的贝壳,空壳,
And until you crack open the shell and
直到你打开壳
start looking inside,
开始在里面,
it doesn't actually get the data for you,
它实际上并不为你获取数据,
And the reason this matters to you is,
这很重要的原因是,
if you go in the debugger, or you do a print statement,
如果你在调试器中,或者做一个print语句,
like this one where you say, for user in recentTweeters
像这样,你说,recentTweeters用户
fetched user whatever, when you print that out,
获取用户,当你打印出来,
it's not gonna print the, a Tweeter user object,
这不是要打印,推特的用户对象,
it's gonna print some kind of faulting shel,
它会打印一些断层替代高能激光,
Because you haven't actually asked for
因为你没有要求
any of the data inside that thing yet, so
任何内部数据的事情,所以
it hasn't faulted yet,
它还没有断,
But if you say, for
但如果你说
user in recentTweeters and say fetched user named, and
用户在recentTweeters说获取用户命名和
now you say user,name, now you are faulting this object in,
现在你说用户名,现在你是断层这个对象,
In fact, this for
事实上,这
loop would fault all these objects in to memory,
循环将所有这些对象在内存故障,
Okay, fetch them all, cuz you're asking for
好的,拿,因为你要求
the name of every single one,
每一个人的名字,
Boom, fault, fault, fault, they're all coming in,
繁荣,错,错,错,他们都进来,
Now, it doesn't do it one by one, it faults in batches,
现在,没有一个接一个,它在批量故障,
it's really high performance, so,
很高的性能,所以,
you know, don't worry about that,
你知道的,不要担心,
But just, I just don't want you to be surprised
但是,我只是不想让你感到惊讶
when you go in the debugger and
当你在调试器中去
you're like, I printed out this Twitter, user and
你喜欢,我打印这个Twitter,用户和
there's no screen name, what's going on?
没有屏幕名,怎么回事?
Well, it hasn't faulted it in,
嗯,还没有断,
In fact, the debugger you could say,
事实上,你可以说,调试器
print the user,name,
打印用户名,
and it would fault it in, okay, give it to you,
它会错,好吧,给你,
All right, I told you I was gonna talk about Core Data
好吧,我告诉你我要讲核心数据
thread safety, so here it is,
线程安全,所以在这里,
NSManagedObjectContext, the context thing,
NSManagedObjectContext,上下文的事情,
that thing that you're sending executes to,
那个东西你发送执行,
that thing that you're hitting save, the things that you're
那件事你保存,你的事情
using to create Tweet, Tweet, subcontext,
子上下文使用创建推特,推特,
colon whatever, that handle on database is not thread safe,
结肠,处理数据库不是线程安全的,
A context can only be used on the queue
一个上下文只能用于队列
that it was created on, period,
上创建,期间,
If you past a context to another queue,
如果你过去一个环境到另一个队列,
like you tried to dispatch off to some
像你试图派出去
global concurrent queue, and you pasted the context, or
全球并发队列,你粘贴的上下文,或
even just pasted a Tweet, okay, that's not gonna work,
只是贴一条微博,好吧,这不是要工作,
cuz that Tweet was created on this other context,
因为,推特上创建另一个上下文,
So in fact, not only the context,
所以实际上,不仅上下文中,
but everything that you create on that context
但是所有你创建上下文
has to all be done in the same queue,
都在相同的队列,
So now you're probably thinking,
现在你可能会想,
well how the heck do I do multithreading then?
到底如何我做多线程呢?
Cuz a database especially, you can imagine, for
特别是因为一个数据库,你可以想象,
temple one to load your database off the main queue,
寺庙加载数据库的一个主要队列,
cuz you, you might be loading lots and lots of things,
因为你,你可能会加载很多很多的东西,
Now your queries,
现在你的查询,
your probably gonna do those on the main queue because,
你可能要做那些队列,因为上主
the user's looking at that information,
用户查看这些信息,
You want it to be highly responsive,
你想要高度敏感,
Okay, it's probably worth, and core data is super fast,
好吧,可能是值得的,和核心数据非常快,
especially with queries,
尤其是在查询,
So, you could probably do that on the main queue,
所以,你可能在主队列,
But loading it up,
但加载它,
you probably don't want to do that,
你可能不想这么做,
All right, so, how do we do multithreading?
好的,那么,我们如何做多线程?
Although that we do multithreading in Core Data,
虽然我们做多线程的核心数据,
is each database can have multiple contexts, okay?
每一个数据库可以有多个上下文?
So, the database underneath, is multithreaded,
所以,下面的数据库,是多线程的,
it can have multiple contexts writing to it,
它可以有多个上下文编写,
Okay, completely different context,
好的,完全不同的背景下,
writing to the same database, in different queue's even, so
写相同的数据库,甚至在不同的队列,所以
it's fully multithreaded,
它是完全多线程,
So that means we had to have a context for every queue,
这意味着我们必须为每个队列上下文,
Whatever queue we're going to access the database,
无论队列我们要访问数据库,
we have to a context in every queue,
我们必须在每个队列上下文,
Now I'm gonna show you how to create a context, or
现在我将向您展示如何创建一个上下文,或
on another queue, so
另一个队列,因此
you can do something with that queue in a second here,
你可以做一些队列在第二个,
But first I want to talk about this important
但首先,我想谈谈这一重要
method in context called performBlock,
方法在上下文中调用performBlock,
performBlock just takes a closure,
performBlock只需要一个闭包,
a closure that takes no arguments,
不带参数的一个闭包,
returns no arguments, and it will ensure, this is
返回没有参数,它将确保,这是
an insurance method, it will ensure that everything inside
一个保险的方法,它将确保一切里面
that closure happens on the right queue for that context,
关闭发生在正确的队列上下文,
Okay, so this, don't get confused,
好吧,这,不感到困惑,
this method does not dispatch, you know,
这种方法不派遣,你知道,
cause background thrading, this is just making sure that,
导致背景thrading,这只是确保,
that closure executes on the right queue,
关闭上执行正确的队列,
So this is a way that you can kind of be safe,
这是一种你可以是安全的,
And some might argue you should put performBlock around
和有些人可能会认为你应该把performBlock
every single call to every Core Data thing you ever do,
每一个叫你曾经所做的每一件核心数据,
because that will ensure that you'll never have a problem
因为这将确保你永远不会有问题
where you're accessing the context not on it's queue,
你访问的上下文而不是队列,
Okay, it accidentally, you got some bad code,
好了,不小心,你有一些糟糕的代码,
Now, that might be a little bit overkill especially if
现在,特别是如果来说可能有点杀鸡用牛刀
you're mostly using the main queue anyway, and
你主要使用主队列,
you really, maybe you only use background queues for
你真的,也许你只使用背景队列
this tiny little bit of processing on the side,
这个小一点的处理,
It's not like you have the tons context and
它不像你有吨上下文和
lots of different queues all going at each other,
很多不同的队列都在彼此,
So, it might be overkill,
因此,它可能是多余的,
But if you're doing anything where you have,
但如果你做任何事,你,
truly have multiple context on multiple queues and
在多个队列和真正有多个上下文
they're access and things, this is a good way to be safe,
他们访问和事物,这是一个好方法是安全的,
Okay, so all this does is it makes it so you are safe,
好的,所以这一切都是它所以你是安全的,
The code inside that block will be executed on the proper
里面的代码块会在适当的执行
queue for that context,
队列上下文,
Even if it has to dispatch, it will do it if it has to,
即使它已经派遣,它将做它如果它,
If it doesn't have to dispatch,
如果它没有派遣,
if you're on the right queue, it'll just execute it, fine,
如果你在正确的队列,它会执行它,很好,
But if you're on the wrong queue right now and
但是如果你在错误的队列现在
you execute this,
你执行这个,
it will dispatch it to the right queue,
它将派遣正确的队列,
There's also performBlockAndWait,
还有performBlockAndWait,
which will get it on the right queue and
这将得到正确的队列和吗
wait until it's done, and then continue in your queue,
等待它完成,然后继续在您的队列,
Okay, but this doesn't really talk about,
好的,但这并没有真正谈论,
how do I get another context in a different thread, right?
我怎么得到另一个背景在一个不同的线程,对吧?
I wanna do some code on another thread,
我想做一些代码在另一个线程,
Where do I get a context?
我得到一个上下文在哪里?
The only context I know how to get right now is viewContext,
我唯一知道如何获得上下文现在viewContext,
That's the main queue's context,
主队列的背景下,
that's the only only one I can get,
这是唯一的只有一个我可以得到,
Okay, well, you're gonna use this really cool method
好的,你会使用这个很酷的方法
in persistentContainer,
在persistentContainer,
This is new in iOS 10 and a really cool method,
这是新的iOS 10和一个很酷的方法,
super cool,
超级酷,
It makes it really easy to do background process on
这使得它很容易做后台进程
Core Data,
核心数据,
It's called performBackgroundTask,
它叫做performBackgroundTask,
Remember, this is a function on persistentContainer that
persistentContainer,记住,这是一个函数
you get from the AppDelegate,
你从在AppDelegate,
And this takes a closure,
这需要一个闭包,
This closure has one argument, the argument is a context,
这个闭包有一个参数,参数是一个背景下,
And that context is appropriate for use
上下文是适合使用
on this other thread that this is going to create for you,
在这另一个线程,这是为您要创建,
So this performBackgroundTask finds another queue,
所以这performBackgroundTask发现另一个队列,
not the main queue, some other queue,
不是主队列,其他队列,
And it creates a context in that other queue, and it
和其他队列创建一个上下文,和它
executes your closure on that other queue in the background,
执行你的关闭其他队列的背景,
Now, it's a convenience method,
现在,这是一个方便的方法,
So if you really needed to control the quality of
所以如果你真的需要控制的质量
service, for example, the queue and all the, okay, well,
服务,例如,队列,所有的,好吧,好吧,
you can't use this,
你不能用这个,
But 99,99% of the time, whatever quality of
但99年,99%的时间,不管质量
service that queue is getting is the right one for
服务队列越来越是正确的
Core Data cuz Core Data knows its business,
核心数据因为知道其业务核心数据,
So you're gonna do it,
所以你要做的,
Now, inside this closure couple of things really
现在,在这个关闭一些东西
be careful of,
小心的,
One, never use viewContext in here,
一个,从不使用viewContext在这里,
Do you see why that would be horrendously bad to
你知道为什么会可怕地不好
use viewContext inside this closure?
这个闭包内使用viewContext吗?
Because this closure by definition is not executing on
因为这个闭包定义不执行
the main queue,
主要的队列,
By definition this closure is on a separate
通过定义这个闭包在一个单独的
queue on a background queue,
在背景队列,队列
That's the whole point of this thing,
这个东西的目的,
is to put this thing on another queue,
把这个东西放在另一个队列,
So never use viewContext in there,
所以不要使用viewContext,
that's why it's in red, okay?
这就是为什么它是红色的,好吗?
The second thing is don't forget to save this context,
第二件事是不要忘记保存这样的背景下,
If you do a whole bunch of stuff in here and
如果你在这里,做一大堆的东西
you don't save, you just did for
你不救,你所做的
nothing cuz you did in memory,
因为你在内存中,
And then this block went away, you're never gonna get that
然后这个块走了,你永远不会得到
context back again, that data is lost,
上下文回来,数据丢失,
Which all gonna leave the heap and then nothing ever happens,
所有要离开堆然后什么事也没发生过,
It never gonna get committed to the database,
它不会被提交到数据库,
So, don't forget to save before you leave,
所以,在你离开之前别忘了保存,
Now, when you save,
现在,当你保存,
it will push it down to the database and
它将数据库和
your other context like your viewContext will see it, okay?
你的其他上下文如viewContext将看到它,好吗?
And so these two contexts, the one that's happening on this
所以这两种情况下,在这发生的
background and the viewContext,
背景和viewContext,
They're working on the same database, so
他们在相同的数据库,所以
when this one saves,
当这一保存,
boom this guys is gonna start seeing those changes,
繁荣这个家伙会开始看到这些变化,
I'm gonna talk a little bit how react to seeing those
我要谈谈如何看到那些反应
changes in a minute here,
变化在一分钟,
Okay, so, everyone understand this?
好的,所以,每个人都明白这一点吗?
Cuz you're gonna have to do this in assignment five,
因为你要做这个作业五,
And I want you to do all your loading off the main queue,
我想让你做所有你的加载主队列,
and all your fetching on the main queue,
和你所有的获取主要的队列,
All right, Core Data is huge,
核心数据是巨大的,
Huge,
巨大的,
I can't cover it all,
我不能掩盖这一切,
It's got optimistic locking, for
它有乐观锁定,
those of you that know about database,
你知道的数据库,
It's got optimistic locking and all that database stuff,
它有乐观锁定和所有数据库的东西,
It has full undo, redo, which is incredible,
全部撤销,重做,这是难以置信的,
It obviously knows how to roll back unsaved changes,
显然,它知道如何回滚未保存的更改,
Okay, if you have changes in memory and
好的,如果你有记忆和变化
you want to roll some of them back,
你想滚回其中的一些,
you can do that before you save,
你可以在保存之前,
It knows about staleness, like, if I make a fetch,
它知道过时,就像,如果我取回,
how long before I really wanna fetch it again because I don't
多久之前我想取回一遍因为我不
trust that the data hasn't changed, right?
相信这些数据并没有改变,对吗?
How long it takes for the data to get stale,
需要多长时间的数据陈旧,
And a lot of other things in the Core Data,
和很多其他的事情在核心数据,
So, I can't cover it all,
所以,我不能涵盖一切,
there's not enough time to do that,
没有足够的时间去做,
Cuz we're trying to talk about a whole another topic about
因为我们试图讨论另一个话题
But you'll want to check the documentation, you won't need
但是你要检查文档,你不需要
Core Data here,
核心数据,
anything else of this stuff to do your homeworks, of course,
其他的东西去做你的作业,当然,
I'm just trying to get you started with this,
我只是想让你开始,
But you need to know that this stuff is in there, so that
但是你需要知道这些东西,所以
one day when you go out and do some significant iOS database
有一天当你走出去,做一些有意义的iOS数据库
stuff, you'll know that these features are out there,
东西,你就会知道,这些特性,
All right, the next topic here is Core Data and UITableView,
好吧,下一个话题是核心数据和UITableView,
As you can imagine, this is a marriage made in heaven, okay?
你可以想象,这是天作之合,好吗?
Because you got this database,
因为你有这个数据库,
got all this big data sets in there and
在那里,所有这些大数据集
what is the UI we use to show big data sets in iOS?
什么是我们使用的UI显示在iOS大数据集吗?
UITableView,
Okay, UITableView is great at showing arbitrary large
好的,UITableView显示任意大型
data sets in our arbitrary UIs, right?
数据集在我们任意的ui,对吧?
We can do custom table view cell,
我们可以自定义表视图单元格,
we can do anything UI we want,
UI我们可以做任何我们想要的,
So, this is so common that Apple has invented this very
这是如此普遍,苹果发明了这个
important class called NSFetchedResultsController,
重要的类称为NSFetchedResultsController,
This is not a viewController, okay?
这不是一个viewController,好吗?
This is a controller that controls Core Data and
这是一个控制器控制核心数据
UITableView talking together,
UITableView说在一起,
but it's not in its fetch results view controller, okay?
但它不是在其获取结果视图控制器,对吧?
And all this NSFetchedResultsController
所有这些NSFetchedResultsController
does is it hooks up an NSFetchRequest that you create
会钩起一个NSFetchRequest您创建的吗
to a UITableView,
UITableView,
And it hooks them up in such a strong way that if anything
这钩子在这样一个强大的方式,如果有的话
changes in the database that would cause that fetch request
数据库的变化会导致获取请求
to return different results, it updates the table
返回不同的结果,它更新表
automatically, you don't have to do anything,
自动,你不需要做任何事情,
So this is an active live hookup between
这是一个活跃的生活之间的连接
the NSFetchRequest and the TableView, okay?
NSFetchRequest TableView,好吗?
Even if some other context are changing the data, it doesn't
即使其他上下文变化数据,它不是
matter, it's always keeping that TableView up to date,
事,它总是保持TableView日期,
So I'm gonna talk about how we do this,
所以我要谈谈我们如何做到这一点,
how we use an NSFetchedResultsController,
我们如何使用一个NSFetchedResultsController,
I'm even gonna provide you some kind of free code
我甚至会提供你一些免费的代码
to do some of it,
做一些,
You'll have to type in a little bit of the rest of it,
你必须输入一个剩下的,
But it's, it's pretty easy to do,
但是,它很容易做到,
So how fundamentally does
那么如何从根本上
NSFetchedResultsController work?
NSFetchedResultsController工作吗?
Two ways, one, it has a delegate and
两种方法,一,它有一个委托和
that delegate you set to be your UITableViewController,
这代表你将UITableViewController,
And whenever the FetchResultsController sees
每当FetchResultsController看到
something happening
发生了一些事情
in the database that would affect that fetchRequest,
fetchRequest数据库中的影响,
it tells the table view controller, hey, do this,
它讲述了表格视图控制器,嘿,这样做,
add this row, add a section, reload this row, whatever,
添加这一行,添加一个部分中,重载这一行,无论如何,
it uses UITableView primitives to update the table, okay?
它使用UITableView原语来更新表,好吗?
I'm gonna show you,
我要告诉你,
I'm gonna give you the code that does that part of it,
我要给你这部分的代码,
that implements the NSFetchedResultsController's
实现NSFetchedResultsController
delegate, okay, so that's one way it does it,
委托,这是它的一种方式,
The other way that the NSFetchedResultsController
NSFetchedResultsController的另一种方式
works is that it provides implementation for
的工作原理是,它提供了实现
all of your UITableView data sources methods, right?
你所有的UITableView数据源的方法,对吧?
Because the contents of your table
因为你的表的内容
are coming out of the database,
的数据库,
so NSFetchedResultsController lets you know all of them, how
所以NSFetchedResultsController让你知道所有这些,怎么做
many sections, how many rows and sections all that stuff,
许多部分,多少行和部分所有的东西,
In fact, this is what it looks like,
事实上,这就是它的样子,
this is the implementation that you're gonna put in to
这是你要投入实施
your controller when you have fetchedResultsController,
你的控制器,fetchedResultsController后,
The first thing you're gonna
你的第一件事
do is you're gonna create a fetchedResultsController, and
做的是你要创建一个,fetchedResultsController,
I'm gonna show you how to do that in a moment,
我将向您展示如何在一个时刻,
And so you're always gonna have a var called
所以你总是会有一个var
fetchedResultsController, and
,fetchedResultsController,
it's gonna be of type NSFetchedResultsController,
它会NSFetchedResultsController类型,
And when you have that var, now you can implement your
当你有var,现在您可以实现您的
sections, number of sections in TableView by saying return
部分,部分数量TableView说回来
fetchedResultsController ,sections,count, okay?
,fetchedResultsController、节、计数,好吗?
Those are a lot of optionals in there, so
这些都是可选的很多,所以
we'll default to one section,
我们将默认为一个部分,
And then to get the number of rows in a section,
然后一节的行数,
you're just gonna say the,
你只会说,
you're gonna get the sections first by saying
你会得到第一个说的部分
fetchedResultsController?,sec- tions,
,fetchedResultsController吗?
And as long as you have some sections, sections,count
只要你有一些部分,部分,计数
greater than zero, then you're gonna return the sections in
大于零,那么你要返回的部分
that section that's passed to you number of objects,
这部分传递给你的对象数量,
Okay, so that code, that's it, that's all of your, those two
好了,这代码,就是这样,这是你的所有,这两个
methods, that's the entire implementation if you're using
方法,如果你使用全部实现
a fetchedResultsController, okay?
,fetchedResultsController ?
And then of course, there's cellForRowAt, okay,
当然,cellForRowAt,好吧,
you gotta implement that, that one too,
你必须实现,一个也
you're gonna use fetchedResultsController,
你会使用,fetchedResultsController,
And the most important thing about cellForRowAt is you need
关于cellForRowAt和最重要的事情是你需要的
to know what's at that row, which thing in my database is
知道在这一行,这东西在我的数据库
at that row in that section in my table,
在这一行,部分在我的表,
And you get that by asking the fetchedResultsController with
通过询问,fetchedResultsController得到
this method objectAtIndexPath,
这个方法objectAtIndexPath,
So you just say fetchedResultsController,
你只是说,fetchedResultsController,
give me the object, and that object is gonna be a tweet, or
给我对象,该对象将是一条微博,或
a Twitter user, or whatever, some entity,
Twitter用户,等等,一些实体,
Give me an object at the index path
给我一个对象索引路径
that cellForRowAt indexPath is asking me for,
,cellForRowAt indexPath问我了,
So now I have the Twitter user or the tweet,
现在我有推特用户或推特,
I can easily load up my UI,
我可以很容易地加载UI,
You know, pass it off to my UI, custom UITableView cell,
你知道,把它从我的UI,定制UITableView细胞,
or if I have a subtitle cell,
如果我有一个副标题,
just take a couple of things out of there and
把几件事情,
put it in the text label in the detailed text label,
把它放在文本标签的详细的文本标签,
you see what I'm saying?
你看到我在说什么吗?
But you can see that the fetchedResultsController,
但是你可以看到,fetchedResultsController,
that code in yellow right there in the middle of
代码用黄色的
cellForRowAt indexPath,
that's doing all the work to figure out what tweet or
这是做所有的工作找出tweet或者什么
what Twitter user is at this row in the table, okay?
什么是Twitter用户在此表中的行,好吗?
So those code on the last slide and
这些代码在最后一张幻灯片
the code on this slide, you'll have to type that code in any
这张幻灯片上的代码,你必须在任何类型的代码
time you're using an NSFetchedResultsController,
当你使用一个NSFetchedResultsController,
Now, on the previous slide, one of the things was var
现在,上一张幻灯片,var的一件事
fetchedResultsController equals something,
,fetchedResultsController等于什么,
So now let's talk about how we create
现在让我们谈谈我们如何创造
a fetchedResultsController, okay?
,fetchedResultsController ?
So this is what the initializer for
这是初始化的
NSFetchedResultsController looks like here,
NSFetchedResultsController看起来像在这里,
It takes a request, a context,
这需要一个请求,一个上下文,
Obviously, it doesn't know what database
显然,它不知道数据库
we're fetching in,
我们抓取,
And then it's got a sectionNameKeyPath,
它有一个sectionNameKeyPath,
That sectionNameKeyPath is the var in
sectionNameKeyPath是var
that entity that, whose value is a string,
实体,其值是一个字符串,
which is the title of the section it's in, okay?
这是一节的标题,好吗?
That's how you do sections with fetchedResultsController,
这就是你,fetchedResultsController部分,
You just have to, and you might have to invent this or
你只需要,你可能不得不发明这个或
even calculate this,
即使是计算这个,
But all of your tweets or all your Twitter users, if they're
但是你所有的微博或者你所有的Twitter用户,如果他们
gonna be in sections, they all have to have a var,
要的部分,他们都必须有一个var,
which is a string, which is the section they're in, okay,
它是一个字符串,他们在一节,好吧,
the name of the section they're in,
他们在一节的名称,
And as long as they have that, then the fetchedResults will,
只要他们有,那么fetchedResults将,
will make the sections and
会使部分和
put them all in there in the right section,
把他们都在正确的部分,
And we'll talk about cacheName in a second here,
我们会讨论cacheName在第二个,
So we have to create a fetchRequest to put in here,
所以我们要创建一个fetchRequest放在这里,
So here's an example of creating a fetchRequest for
这里有一个例子创建fetchRequest
tweets, right?
微博,对吧?
So you recognize that first line there,
所以你认识到第一行,
creating a fetchRequest for tweets,
创建一个fetchRequest推,
And I'm gonna sort by when the tweets were created, okay,
我将通过创建微博时,好吧,
when the tweet was tweeted out,
当推了推特,
And I'm gonna look for all the tweets whose tweeter's name
我要寻找所有的推特的推特的名字
equals some name, the name, okay?
等于某个名字,这个名字,好吗?
So it's gonna get all those tweets, and
所以它会得到所有这些推文,
I'm gonna set that request as the first argument there,
我要设置请求作为第一个参数,
to NSFetchedResultsController,
NSFetchedResultsController,
By the way, notice NSFetchedResultsController is
顺便说一下,请注意NSFetchedResultsController
also a generic type, and NSFetchedResultsController can
也是一个泛型类型,NSFetchedResultsController可以
only control fetches for a certain type,
只有控制获取特定类型,
So you have to say what type, okay, what type of entity that
所以你必须说什么类型、什么类型的实体
your FetchController is doing, and these are the same type of
FetchController做,这些都是同一类型的
things that are in the rows of your table,
在你的表的行,
Now that cacheName at the bottom is interesting,
既然cacheName底部很有趣,
That is actually going to permanently cache the results,
要永久缓存结果,
it's gonna get the results out of the database and
它会从数据库中得到的结果
In other words,
换句话说,
store on disk the result in some internal format,
存储在磁盘上的结果在某些内部格式,
And that's cool, and that storage, by the way,
,那很酷,存储,顺便说一下,
if you quit your app and come back,
如果你退出你的应用和回来,
it will still use that cache, so it's quite efficient,
它仍然会使用缓存,所以它很有效,
But you have to be a little bit careful,
但你必须小心一点,
You cannot change anything about your request,
你不能改变任何关于你的要求,
As soon as you change anything about your request, like
只要你改变任何关于你的要求,
the name, the tweeter,name that you're searching for, or
推特的名字,名字,你正在寻找,或
what you're sorting by, or anything,
你排序,或任何
Now that cache is invalid, and you'll have to invalidate that
现在缓存是无效的,你必须无效
cache, okay, and there's an API in there for doing that,
缓存,这样做有一个API,
You can pass nil there if you don't wanna do the caching,
你可以通过nil缓存,如果你不想做
which for most reasonable sized datasets perfectly fine,
这对于大多数合理大小的数据集非常好,
you don't really need the caching,
你真的不需要缓存,
But I just wanna emphasize that if you change your
但我想强调的是,如果你改变
request, your cache is now invalid,
缓存的请求,你现在是无效的,
And about that section key thing, something to be careful
和部分关键,要小心
about there, too, is that whatever your sortDescriptors
大概在这里,无论你sortDescriptors
say that your rows would sort in, that has to be
会说你行,
exactly the same order that your sections was sorted in,
相同的订单,你的部分是按照,
In other words, the FetchedResultsController
换句话说,,FetchedResultsController
doesn't know how to like move things around
不知道如何像四处移动
because they sort out of order of their sections,
因为他们解决的部分,
That's why a lot of times that we're doing sections,
这就是为什么很多时候我们做的部分,
the first sortDescriptor will be sort by the section key
第一sortDescriptor将是关键的部分
name var, right?
var名字,对吧?
And then the second one will be sort by what we
然后第二个将由我们
really wanna sort by, because we have to make sure
真的想排序,因为我们必须确保
that our entire table is sorted in section order,
节中,我们整个表排序顺序,
You see why?
你知道为什么吗?
Cuz otherwise it's just weird,
因为否则就奇怪,
things would all be in the wrong places,
事情都是在错误的地方,
So keyThatSaysWhichAttributeIsTh-
因此keyThatSaysWhichAttributeIsTh -
eSectionName has to sort in the same order as your
eSectionName必须在相同的顺序进行排序
sortDescriptors,
Okay, now, I told you that NSFetchedResultsController
好的,现在,我告诉你,NSFetchedResultsController
watches Core Data,
手表的核心数据,
It sees changes happening in there, and it updates it,
它看到变化,更新它,
And it does that with its delegate, okay?
和它的委托,对吧?
Its delegate wants to be the tableView,
它代表想要表视图,
be the tableViewController, rather,
有这个表,
Cuz it's gonna tell the tableViewController, and
因为它会告诉表,
it sends messages like this,
这样发送消息,
So this is a typical NSFetchedResultsController
这是一个典型的NSFetchedResultsController
delegate method,
委托方法,
Controller did change add indexPath for change type, and
控制器做了添加indexPath改变类型,
here's the new indexPath,
这是新的indexPath,
Okay, and these change types might be deleted or
好了,这些可能被删除或者改变类型
inserted or modified or whatever,
插入或修改,
Now, you have to put the code in there that would call
现在,你必须把代码放进去,电话
the right methods on the tableView to get the sections
正确的方法tableView部分
inserted or deleted or rows added or whatever,
插入或删除或添加行,
But I'm gonna give you that code for free, okay, and
但我还是要给你免费代码,好的,
the demo that I'm gonna do on Wednesday,
周三我要做的演示,
I'm gonna have a class called fetchedResultsTableViewContro-
我要上课叫fetchedResultsTableViewContro -
ller, which is gonna be a class,
噢,这是一个类,
And you can make that to be the super class of your
你可以让你的超类
UITableViewController,
And you'll just inherit this implementation of
你会继承这个实现的
the delegate, okay?
委托,对吧?
Yes, cuz that's what I just said,
是的,因为这就是我刚才说的,
Okay, so when you're using core data in UITableView,
好的,所以当你在UITableView使用核心数据,
the things to remember are, you're going to subclass
要记住的事情是,你将子类
fetchedResultsTableViewContro- ller,
fetchedResultsTableViewContro——噢,
the thing I'm gonna give you, so that you implement
我要的东西给你,以便你实现
NSFetchedResultsController delegate,
NSFetchedResultsController委托,
You're going to add a var to your UITableViewController
你要添加一个var UITableViewController
called fetchedResultsController, and
叫,fetchedResultsController,
you're gonna set its value to be
你要设置它的值
an NSFetchedResultsController with the fetchRequest that you
一个NSFetchedResultsController fetchRequest你
want, okay, that you want to populate your table,
想要的,好吧,你想填充表,
Then you're gonna implement your UITableView data source
然后你会实现你的UITableView数据源
methods using fetchedResultsController var
使用,fetchedResultsController var的方法
methods, just like I showed you in the slides,
方法,就像我给你的幻灯片,
character for character,
字符的字符,
you can use the exact same things that are on the slide,
您可以使用相同的事情在幻灯片上,
Okay, and then it's all gonna magically work, all you'll
好了,然后它会神奇地工作,你会
have to do is inside your cellForRowAt indexPath,
要做的就是在你cellForRowAt indexPath,
you'll have the object, the tweet,
你有对象,推特,
or the Twitter user, you just gotta load up your UI,
或Twitter用户,您只需要加载UI,
After you have all this set up,
所有这些设置后,
then you can proceed to using the fetchedResultsController
然后你可以继续使用,fetchedResultsController
in your tableViewController,
在你的表,
First thing you have to do is perform fetch on
你首先要做的就是执行获取
the fetchedResultsController,
,fetchedResultsController,
That will cause it to go out and do your NSFetchRequest,
这将导致出去你NSFetchRequest呢,
basically,
基本上,
It's not gonna pull all the data over, but
它不会把所有的数据,但是
it's going to basically bring over, do the same thing as if
基本上它会带过来,如果做同样的事情
you had executed the fetchRequest yourself, and
你执行了fetchRequest自己,
then you're gonna wanna do tableView View,reloadData,
然后你会想做tableView看来,reloadData,
And that's because you want all of your datasource
因为你想要你所有的数据源
methods to be called, and you know that we've implemented
方法被调用,你知道我们已经实现了
all of them in terms of our fetch results controller as
我们所有人而言,获取结果控制器
showed on the previous slides there,
显示在前面的幻灯片,
And the only other thing you want to remember to do
唯一的另一件事你要记住
is set your fetch results controller's delegate to be
设置你的获取结果控制器的委托是什么
yourself and, again, we use that fetch results table view
自己,再一次,我们使用,获取结果表视图
controller code that added the delegate methods for
控制器添加的委托方法的代码
the fetch results controller to the UITableView controller
获取结果控制器UITableView控制器
until we can do all the things that is necessary to
直到我们可以做所有的事情是必要的
be a fetchedResultsController delegate,
是一个,fetchedResultsController委托,
And what that buys you is that anytime in the database
你购买是随时在数据库中
changes that would affect the NSFetchedRequest
这将影响NSFetchedRequest变化
that you wired up to your fetchedResultsController,
你连接到你的,fetchedResultsController,
Then, it will use that delegate to ask the table view
然后,它将使用委托问表视图
to update the rows or sections,
更新行或部分,
whatever happened to change,
无论发生了什么变化,
So let me talk a little bit about what's coming up here,
让我谈谈即将发生的事,
on Wednesday, I'm gonna do a big demo that shows you all of
周三,我要做一个演示程序,展示了你的所有
this stuff, as usual,
这个东西,像往常一样,
Assignment five is going out on Wednesday,
作业五是周三,
it'll be due the next Wednesday,
由于下一个周三,
It's going to be to add Core Data stuff to your Smashtag,
这将是添加Smashtag核心数据,
On Friday, very relevant section,
周五,相关部门,
It's using CloudKit to do a database,
这是使用CloudKit数据库,
Okay? Now, Core Data and CloudKit,
好吧?
what, what are they, how are they related?
它们是什么,它们是如何联系起来的?
Well, Core Data is for
核心数据
doing things that you would do with a relational database,
做你会做的事与关系数据库中,
these powerful queries and searches and things like that,
这些强大的查询和搜索之类的东西,
Cloud Kit is, what if you wanted to have a database
云设备,如果你想要一个数据库
on the network, in the cloud, okay?
在网络上,在云中,好吗?
A network that's being shared between multiple people or
网络在多个人之间共享的或
even by a single person on multiple,
即使是一个人在多个,
on multiple of their devices, or whatever,
在多个设备,等等,
So there quite different in the way they approach things,
因此,他们做事的方式完全不同,
In Core Data, we do the schema using this visual mapper,
核心数据,我们使用这种视觉映射器的模式,
In CloudKit, it's essentially schema on the fly,
在CloudKit,它本质上是模式,
As you start saving vars,
当你开始储蓄增值,
it starts making this schema up for you, so
为你开始制作这个模式,所以
it's a very different kind of way of thinking about,
这是一个非常不同的思考方式,
You don't think of it from a scheme of design point,
你不把它从方案的设计角度,
In advance, there's kind of more organic as you go and
提前,有更多的有机你去
also you don't have to,
你也不需要,
you know, kind of create this whole scheme of front and
你知道,创建前后的整个计划
describe it, you can describe it as you use it essentially,
描述它,你可以描述它本质上使用它,
So it's a very interesting comparison between the two,
这是一个非常有趣的两者之间的比较,
I wish I had time to do CloudKit,
我希望我有时间做CloudKit,
Last quarter, I had the extra lectures,
上个季度,我有额外的讲座,
I was able to do CloudKit as a whole lecture but,
我能够做CloudKit讲座作为一个整体,但
we'll have to do it as a Friday section this week so,
我们必须做本周周五部分,
don't miss that,
不要错过,
Next Monday is a holiday,
下星期一是假期,
So no lecture and then next Wednesday,
所以没有课,然后在下周三,
I'm gonna go over your requirements for
我要超过你的要求
the final project, which are required to do,
的最后一个项目,需要做什么,
And I'm also gonna have a lecture as well on AutoLayout,
我也会有一个讲座在自动布局,
We'll finally get to Autolayout and
我们最后会自动布局
how do that Autolayout stuff,
如何自动布局的东西,
I'd say, I just wanted to show you that and
我想说,我只是想告诉你,
I will see you all on Wednesday,
周三我将看到你所有,
>> For more please visit us on Stanford,edu,
> >更多信息请访问我们在斯坦福,edu,